Theme Tune: Music
Al: hello farmers and welcome to another episode of the harvest season my name is al and we're here
Vincent: And my name is Vincent.
Al: today to talk about vr woo cottagecore games but we're going to talk about vr because
Vincent: Woo!
Vincent: In VR.
Al: vincent just got a Steam Deck
Al: and I also just got a Steam Deck woo
Vincent: Yes, I did.
Vincent: And somebody else got that Steam Deck as well.
Al: because we are suckers spending a thousand quid
Al: on this device well yeah well no I guess not really because valve have done two other handhelds
Vincent: Yeah, on a first-generation device.
Vincent: Well, actually, no.
Al: before it's just that this is the first standalone handheld they've done so
Vincent: Yeah. So technically not. Yes. Okay. You're right. Yes. Not first generation.
Al: not not for it depends how you think about it I can see why you could argue that it's first
Al: generation because it's their first standalone one but yeah they have it's not completely
Al: new anyway we're going to talk about that we're going to talk about that both on its own because
Vincent: Yes, yeah, yeah.
Al: it's just an interesting conversation and we both want to talk about our nice fancy toys that we just
Al: bought um but also I think we should talk about cottagecore games farming etc because I just
Al: played a new uh vr farming game um and spoiler alert I felt sick playing it so that was a great
Al: start. But I think we can just talk about these things in
Al: general, because I've this is, I think, the second one I've done and the third one I've
Al: talked about. So we can probably kind of come to some sort of interesting discussion, I
Al: think. But we will come to that later. Before that, we have the game news. We also have because
Al: it's a new month. We've got I know what you released last month. First of all, Vincent,
Vincent: Well, gaming-wise, aside from, you know, Steam Deck-related items, I have been playing quite a bit of Final Fantasy XIV recently, so, yes.
Al: ah this game a game i've heard other people talk about
Vincent: Yes, I'm sure there's going to be some listeners that will be glad that this is a topic.
Vincent: But yeah, I've been playing quite a bit.
Al: You've played this for quite a while, haven't you?
Al: You're not new to it.
Vincent: Not really.
Vincent: Well, so I've played a little bit, what was it, maybe like a few years ago now?
Vincent: When Hannah first started, I started at the same time as well, or when our mutual friend Hannah first started.
Vincent: But I fell off of it.
Vincent: You know, it's one of those things where I took a break and I came back and I don't remember what I was doing.
Vincent: And in an MMO, it's a much larger scale, much larger world.
Vincent: So I fell off a bit, a little bit.
Vincent: But then recently, once, you know, when it had the Dawntrail release and a lot more people tried it out, I jumped out.
Vincent: I jumped back on, and this time I was able to stick to it.
Vincent: And actually, just very recently, I finished the first, you know, I guess you can call it the first part of the story.
Al: Fair enough. So other than, right, try, I want you to try something. Sell me on the game without saying it has farming. Because that's all anybody ever says about this game. I want you to sell me on the game without just saying it has farming in it.
Vincent: so I i know well I know you're a fan of rpgs um it is so I think of like a good way to to put it so
Vincent: there's a lot of things to do activities to do in the game it's not just purely you know obviously
Vincent: there's the main storyline uh which if you want to follow that you can but otherwise I think what's
Vincent: neat about this game is that you know once you get to a certain point uh you know you can start
Vincent: watering off at the very
Vincent: beginning but probably you know you're going to be locked out
Vincent: to a lot of things so you probably have to do
Vincent: the storyline a
Vincent: little bit until you get to a certain point
Vincent: but once you get to a certain point it really
Vincent: opens up in terms of all the things you
Vincent: can do you know you can continue
Vincent: on the storyline you can
Vincent: get other jobs
Vincent: in there so there's
Vincent: your classic
Vincent: I guess you know I'm not
Vincent: an expert on terminology I'm trying to remember to make sure
Vincent: we use the right terminology
Vincent: for this but you know there's your basic jobs
Vincent: right your paladin
Vincent: your archer and you know healer
Vincent: and all that but this game
Vincent: also has a lot of side
Vincent: side
Vincent: jobs that you can get
Vincent: so like a miner
Vincent: fisher sort of the
Vincent: gathering jobs and also crafting
Vincent: jobs so you know you can pair it up
Vincent: so you can say okay I'm going to be a
Vincent: paladin as my main
Vincent: you know
Vincent: job
Vincent: but then I can also pick up the miner
Vincent: and level that up as well
Vincent: aspect
Vincent: well and then
Vincent: once you mine enough ores and stuff
Vincent: then you can use that to
Vincent: do the crafting
Vincent: part of it
Vincent: so you know build armors
Vincent: or build weapons and whatnot
Vincent: so
Vincent: that would be my
Vincent: my
Vincent: I guess my
Vincent: not very good
Vincent: but kind of my sales pitch
Vincent: so that's another piece I liked of it
Al: Interesting. How prevalent is the MMO part of it?
Vincent: it's not that prevalent
Vincent: at least you know
Vincent: where I'm at
Vincent: it's been very you know
Vincent: the first part
Vincent: the first few
Vincent: dungeons that you had
Vincent: to do
Vincent: was very doable
Vincent: with just NPCs
Vincent: so you don't have to
Vincent: queue up with other people
Vincent: if you don't want to
Vincent: I'm now at the point
Vincent: of the game where I
Vincent: you know
Vincent: you have to queue up
Vincent: with other people
Vincent: but even then
Vincent: it's
Vincent: you know
Vincent: there's a built-in system
Vincent: in there that you can
Vincent: easily queue up
Vincent: with other people
Vincent: you don't have to
Vincent: interact with
Vincent: you know
Vincent: others if you don't want to
Vincent: So you can treat us like a single player game with just,
Vincent: that there's other people around it playing.
Vincent: So it's not,
Vincent: it doesn't require a lot of MMO coordination or whatnot,
Al: okay yeah I i suspect yeah I suspect that's not a huge issue I i think if I ever got to the point
Vincent: if you don't want to.
Vincent: But again,
Vincent: I'm also not at the end game part of it where you may need to get with more
Al: where I was playing this game and I got to like end game I think i'm probably enjoying it enough
Al: that I can just deal with whatever they need me I need to deal with right um the issue with all
Al: these things is like it's a game i've never played it's a massive game it is
Al: you know where to start you know I kind of I guess I feel the way same way towards that as
Al: some people too towards stars you where you're just like there's so much to do and it's like where do
Al: you start and how do you start and my my issue with new games is always that it's the if i'm starting a
Al: game i'm almost committing to play this for like you know at least 10 hours that's a big commitment for
Vincent: Oh yeah, definitely. And if you're not careful, you can easily get lost and overwhelm yourself
Vincent: in the beginning. Luckily, we have a lot of mutual friends that play this game. So I was able to ask
Al: Yeah, yeah.
Vincent: advice in terms of, hey, should I be just focusing on one thing or should I just try to do everything?
Vincent: And I got that advice that they told me, just focus on the main story quest until you get to
Vincent: a certain point
Vincent: because otherwise
Vincent: he's just going
Al: OK. Well, I don't talk about too much more about it because maybe I might be talking about it in a future episode.
Vincent: much to handle.
Al: No promises. We'll see. I don't know what you're talking about. Anything else you've been up to?
Vincent: hint hint ah so that's mainly the other thing that i've been uh playing a lot recently um is
Vincent: the witcher 3 uh remastered or I guess re uh yeah the remastered version just came out
Al: Mm-hmm.
Vincent: um you know it's been a game that's has interested me for a while i've i've dabbled in it a little
Vincent: bit but i've never stuck with it um so when the remaster came out I i already had it in my library
Vincent: So I booted up and I think now I'm finally...
Al: Fair enough.
Al: I don't think I've ever played any of their games.
Vincent: I don't think that's probably not in your genre wheelhouse. I would say the remaster is pretty good, though. My main complaint initially when I first played it was that the combat felt very floaty. It doesn't feel good. I wouldn't say that they've completely fixed that, but it's much better.
Vincent: now
Vincent: I don't know
Vincent: if it's like
Vincent: you know
Vincent: I can't quantify it
Vincent: it's placebo
Vincent: but it does feel
Vincent: better for me
Al: Mm-hmm okay all right well I yeah no if you were going to say something say
Vincent: so
Vincent: oh no
Vincent: go ahead
Vincent: oh no no
Al: that's fine uh I well I suspect you've also been playing Beat Saber is that true to say
Vincent: go ahead
Vincent: oh yes
Vincent: yes
Al: well tell me because this this will be your first time playing
Vincent: that's
Vincent: as well
Vincent: it's been
Vincent: taking up
Vincent: a lot of
Vincent: my time
Vincent: yeah so
Al: playing Beat Saber since you got the Steam Deck presumably
Al: okay yeah
Vincent: it's my
Vincent: first time
Vincent: playing
Vincent: well I've
Vincent: I've played
Vincent: Beat Saber
Vincent: you know
Vincent: at friend's
Vincent: it's the first
Vincent: time I've
Vincent: actually
Vincent: played it
Vincent: for an
Vincent: extended period
Vincent: of time
Vincent: so
Vincent: it's
Vincent: it is much
Vincent: more difficult
Vincent: than I
Vincent: thought
Al: Yeah.
Vincent: because
Vincent: aside from
Vincent: you know
Vincent: when you're
Vincent: just playing
Vincent: like one-off
Vincent: easy songs
Vincent: it feels
Vincent: easy
Vincent: but then
Vincent: when you
Vincent: start trying
Vincent: to
Vincent: you know
Vincent: oh I
Vincent: want to
Vincent: try to
Vincent: rap
Vincent: difficulty
Vincent: or try
Vincent: other songs
Vincent: then it's
Vincent: it's much
Vincent: more difficult
Vincent: than what
Vincent: I when I
Vincent: expected
Vincent: I've had
Al: I think that's a standard that's a standard rhythm game thing, because I did the same with Guitar Hero the first time I played it.
Al: I was like, oh, this is going to be easy. You're just pressing buttons at the right time.
Al: And then you're like, oh, no, this is this is a skill that you need to learn.
Vincent: Oh, yeah, yeah, I had to turn off the game over, you know, or it doesn't fail you after, you know, if you miss a certain number of beats, I had to turn that off.
Al: yeah can I also I would also suggest there is a setting I can't remember what it is but there's a
Al: setting um I think it might be like a more detailed hud or something and it shows you the length of
Al: the song and how far through the song you are for some reason that is not on by default but it is on
Al: it is a setting there um which it just changed how I view the game entirely because I hate when
Al: you're like part of the way through something like I don't know am I nearly done
Al: like i'm really struggling now do I like because I i don't do the um continue like no failure I i i
Al: want to be able to get through it without failure but obviously i've been playing it for a lot longer
Al: than you um and so I was I i when you get to a point where you're like i'm almost like i'm really
Al: struggling am I nearly there do I push through to the end or do I just like take a break and come
Al: back later and if i'm like 30 seconds away i'm like I want to finish this whereas if you look
Al: through and you're not even halfway through you're like I need I need a break from this um
Al: and having that timer it was a massive
Vincent: Oh, okay. I'm going to try that. Yeah, I've been, especially when I play like someone from some of the song packs, like, you know, the pop songs that I would just have to remember like, okay, is this like the second chorus? It's like the bridge, you know, how far along are we?
Al: yeah yeah yeah I really don't know why it's not default on it feels like
Al: yeah I don't know it's it's like it's not an accessibility thing it's just seeing the time
Al: through the song like I just I want to see how far through the song we are so yeah that is a
Vincent: Yeah, no way.
Al: setting get it enabled the other one I have on is uh restart on failure so you don't have to like
Vincent: Okay, perfect.
Vincent: I'll need to try that out.
Al: it just automatically restarts I i enjoy that because i'm pushing through into to the
Vincent: Oh, okay. I may try it out too. Yeah, because one of the things that annoyed me is that you have to, you know, click and try to, it's a lot of clicks to go back to where you were when you're starting.
Al: yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah whereas if you have that on it literally just it's like a two or three
Al: seconds and then it restarts the song um which is is great the other one the other thing that is
Al: useful is you can play the songs in practice mode um which means you can either you could you like
Al: it's the same as like not no failure um but it allows you to like change the speed if you want
Al: to practice certain sections. And it allows you to say, I want to start the song at this
Al: point. So if there's a part like two thirds, quite common is like there's a bridge two thirds of
Al: the way through the song, which is like the hardest bit of the song. And you're like, I don't
Al: want to have to keep playing through the song to get back to practice that bit. You can start the
Al: practice at an exact second, which is very handy for practicing bits like that.
Vincent: Oh, interesting. Okay. I'm going to try that out. So yeah, there's certain, I'm getting used to it now, but there's certain things that come up that I always struggle with. Like if it's like two, you know, at the same time, it's going different directions or like the one that's usually on the left suddenly appears on the right.
Al: yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah so if you're finding the specific bits of songs
Al: that you're struggling with go go in and try the practice mode it's very handy
Al: so obviously I have also been playing beat saber um I started replaying it when when vincent got
Vincent: Oh, interesting. All right. I'm going to try it out too.
Al: his steam frame I was like oh i've not played beat saber in ages um because I played it like
Al: every day for months
Al: a couple years ago
Al: and then just
Al: fall off these things right
Al: and I was like
Al: I don't want to wait
Al: for my Steam frame
Al: and also I'm going
Al: to be keeping
Al: because I have a
Al: MetaQuest 3
Al: I'm going to have
Al: I'm going to keep that
Al: because I have
Al: almost all the
Al: packs of songs
Al: and I'm like
Al: I don't want to rebuy
Al: all of them again
Al: on Steam
Al: so what I think
Al: I'm going to do
Al: is probably
Al: buy new packs
Al: on Steam
Al: but keep my quest
Al: for the old packs
Al: if I want to go back
Al: and play them
Al: so obviously
Al: I've rebuy the game
Al: on Steam
Al: but
Al: game itself is not stupidly expensive
Al: but it's like if you want to buy
Al: all of the packs that is a lot of money
Al: yep yep
Vincent: The packs are where they get you.
Al: so uh yeah
Al: I will be keeping that for those songs
Al: but uh yeah so I went
Al: I was like I need to get back into playing it and i
Al: realized how out
Al: of practice I got
Al: it's the muscles
Al: in your arms they're not muscles you use for
Al: a lot of things so you they become
Al: achy very quickly
Al: yeah
Vincent: Oh, yeah. Oh, I've had to, my first few times had to take breaks, not because of, you know, the battery or the VR, but because my arms were tired.
Al: yeah yeah yeah
Al: all right so we'll talk more
Al: about vr later um i've also
Al: well speaking oh no we've got
Al: another vr thing isle of food that was the vr
Al: game vr farming game that I was playing
Al: uh we'll talk about that later but
Al: that's the thing i've been playing but the other thing
Al: is i've finished marvel's wolverine
Al: I finished the story I decided
Al: not
Al: to 100 percent it uh I can talk about that in a minute why but
Al: overall I would say this game is
Al: fine
Al: I i think so I think I enjoyed the story it's it's hard to talk about the story
Vincent: Okay, from an overall standpoint or from a story or gameplay standpoint?
Al: without spoilering things um
Al: I mean if you're interested in in what the story is maybe I can do a spoiler
Al: section at the very end of the podcast but
Al: I i enjoyed the story it's it's you know it's not kind of your I i'm not a
Al: aware of it being uh an adapted x-men story of any kind um there are bits and pieces that
Al: obviously feel similar to lots of stories like from the trailers you might have seen
Al: that the morlocks are in it so there's there's obviously stuff related to them that can have
Al: happened in all that all of them um but yeah it's I don't know I i don't I can't remember
Al: how much was public are you aware of who wolverine is working with at the beginning
Vincent: Uh, no.
Vincent: Well, but also, this is probably a game I'm never going to play because I don't have a PS5, so...
Al: yeah all right maybe maybe let's talk about it now i'll i'll this is the end of the what we've
Al: been up to section and talked about everything else so i'll put in a chapter here of spoilers
Al: if you don't want to hear the spoilers for marvel's wolverine click the the next chapter
Al: and you can go to I know what you released last month um so the game starts off with you
Al: as wolverine waking up in a forest and uh you see there's a there's someone who's come and they've
Al: said like oh I can help you I have a place for people and you're like oh interesting is this
Al: Professor X as he comes
Al: to no it's not Professor X
Al: it's Nathaniel Essex
Al: and so
Vincent: Oh, interesting.
Al: immediately you're like okay so I know
Al: who the end game baddie is then
Al: obviously we're coming to Mr. Sinister
Vincent: Hmm.
Al: and
Al: obviously that is true that is
Al: who the final boss is Mr. Sinister
Al: but it's interesting
Al: because
Al: Essex has created
Al: Team X which is
Al: Wolverine, Sabretooth
Al: and Mystique
Al: was there anyone else
Al: I feel like there was someone else but maybe they weren't
Al: there very much
Al: anyway so he's created this
Al: team and you're you know like a black
Al: ops mutant team taking out
Al: Trask is kind of your first
Al: baddie of the game
Al: and he's building a
Al: sentinel and you
Al: fight the hand at one point
Al: and then near the end of the game
Al: after you've defeated
Al: Trask and you've defeated the hand
Al: Essex
Al: takes over Trask's
Al: facility
Al: and rebuilds
Al: the sentinels
Al: but rebuilds them
Al: not to hunt down
Al: and kill mutants
Al: but to hunt down
Al: mutants whose powers
Al: haven't come out
Al: and take them
Al: and then they have
Al: the
Al: I'm sure this is
Al: something in the comics
Al: but there's like a
Al: I can't remember
Al: what it's called
Al: there's a machine
Al: that brings out
Al: latent mutant abilities
Al: and so he's
Al: he's got that
Al: so he's got the sentinels
Al: going out and grabbing
Al: people who are
Al: who are dormant mutants
Al: and bringing them
Al: and giving them
Al: their powers
Al: obviously that's not great
Al: so that's that's
Al: that whole thing
Al: but yeah it just
Al: it's interesting
Al: how it starts off
Al: clearly trying to do
Al: the misdirect of like
Al: oh it's Professor X
Al: no no it's not
Al: it's Nathaniel Essex
Al: and you're working
Al: with Sabretooth
Al: at least at the start
Al: obviously that does
Al: not last
Al: surprise surprise
Al: but the most
Al: interesting point
Al: to me is
Al: you'll probably
Al: have no scene
Al: in some of the stuff
Al: that Jean
Al: Jean Grey is in
Al: in the game
Al: and so she's been
Al: working with
Al: she's been
Al: protecting the Morlocks
Al: so when you go
Al: and try and help them
Al: you come across Jean
Al: and you get to know her
Al: and there's
Al: you kind of
Al: she
Al: she doesn't really
Al: join Team X
Al: but you kind of
Al: both of you
Al: start working together
Al: and kind of clearly used
Al: you're starting to do things
Al: that Essex doesn't want you to do
Al: and he starts getting a bit weird
Al: and there's issues with Sabretooth
Al: and blah, blah, blah.
Al: And then at some point you end up,
Al: so a big part of it,
Al: which is a standard Wolverine thing,
Al: is like you don't have
Al: a bunch of your memories, right?
Al: And so you're uncovering memories as you go.
Al: And there's a point where you're uncovering
Al: quite a big memory
Al: and it turns out that you knew Jean before,
Al: But you...
Al: Essex essentially kind of broke you, your mind, and brainwashed you to kill Jean.
Al: But then, and we don't know how this...
Al: So this one thing is I'm not 100% sure which way this is.
Al: But either she was resurrected because of the phoenix.
Al: Or it's not technically the same person, but she's like...
Al: The phoenix has inhabited another person who ends up becoming Jean.
Al: It's not quite clear what the deal is.
Al: But she doesn't have her memories of your time together.
Al: But then she regains them.
Al: And you regain them.
Al: So now you both have the memories of you being together before.
Al: But you having killed Jean.
Al: But then, and this is where it's really weird.
Al: Right at the end, Jean wipes your memory.
Vincent: Oh, okay.
Al: And so you no longer have the memory of being with Jean.
Al: And I don't know whether I missed something as to whether there's a reason
Al: does this, but she then tells you about those memories, but you don't have those memories.
Al: So you're like, Wolverine's like reacting to those memories, being like,
Al: I believe what you're saying, but I don't have those feelings sort of thing.
Al: And then he goes off into the world.
Al: It's all a bit weird.
Al: But I thought that they're like, oh, you had a life before, but then neither of you have
Al: memories of that as a reveal was quite an interesting thing.
Al: And I did like the Logan and Jean relationship building in that way.
Al: I think quite often in X-Men stuff,
Al: you see some Logan and Jean stuff
Al: and you see some Scott and Jean stuff,
Al: but there's always like that tension.
Al: I thought it was interesting to see
Al: Jean and Logan developing a relationship
Al: without that tension there with Scott,
Al: which was, I thought that was quite interesting.
Vincent: oh yeah are there other x-men that show up or is it just or the other cast of x-men or
Al: There, I don't, I'm trying to remember if there was,
Al: I think that was, that's...
Al: There's obviously quite a lot of Morlocks, including Leech, who dies.
Al: But I don't think there were any...
Al: There's a couple of kind of hints at other characters.
Al: Like, there's a file of one that could have been rogue, but not quite sure.
Al: But there's kind of, like, hints that it might have been rogue, but you don't see her.
Al: I don't think there was any, like, other actual X-Men characters that you encountered.
Al: But the one other thing is that throughout the story, you get these voices in your head that's, like, telling you stuff.
Al: And if you don't have the subtitles on, it's a mystery as to who this character is until the end.
Al: If you do have subtitles on, it gives it away the first time you hear it, as it subtitles it as Apocalypse.
Vincent: oh my god oh
Al: And you're like, oh, apparently Apocalypse is talking to me.
Al: I don't know how I would know that.
Al: But, like, right at the end, there's, like, a post-credits scene with Sabretooth.
Al: Being taken over by Apocalypse, basically.
Al: And clearly setting up for a future story.
Al: But it's just so funny how they're, like, they put in, like, they should have just...
Al: It's not an unusual thing in subtitles where you've got a character who's not named at this point.
Al: And they say, like, unknown voice or question marks or something like that.
Al: But for some reason, they decided to spoil the fact that it was Apocalypse.
Al: And I think subtitles are on by default.
Al: It's not like I just turned them on.
Al: I would have
Al: turned them on
Al: because I like
Al: subtitles, but I'm
Al: pretty sure they're
Al: on by default.
Vincent: Oh, OK, that's what I was going to ask,
Vincent: because I know things being on by default has been--
Al: Right, okay.
Al: I think this game
Al: does make some
Al: stupid decisions,
Al: and I also think
Al: that people are
Al: complaining about
Al: things pointlessly
Al: in some cases.
Al: I think
Al: I will agree that the
Al: quick time events
Al: in this game are
Al: weird and
Al: pointless, but
Al: personally, I think
Al: quick time events are
Al: pointless full stop,
Al: right?
Al: I don't find them
Al: and I think
Al: it just feels like
Al: a way to kind of
Al: like keep people
Al: engaged in the
Al: cut scene or
Al: something.
Al: Like, I don't
Al: really get why
Al: people continue to
Al: use quick time
Al: events, and
Al: Wolverine has taken
Al: it to the extreme
Al: where you can't
Al: fail them, which
Al: is true.
Al: There's no setting
Al: to allow you to
Al: fail quick time
Al: events.
Al: There is a setting
Al: that is automatically
Al: press the buttons,
Al: but if you don't
Al: have that turned on
Al: it's just that the quick time event
Al: doesn't do anything until you click it
Al: you can't fail them
Al: which I really don't care about
Al: but then I wouldn't want them
Al: as a quick time event anyway
Al: right
Al: I do understand why they don't fail
Al: because this is Wolverine
Al: right
Al: like Wolverine
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: immortal being basically
Al: right
Al: like he can't really die
Al: and so the idea of having failure
Al: in quick time events for Wolverine
Al: I don't understand why they didn't do them
Al: but what I don't understand is
Al: why they did the quick time events at all
Vincent: Yeah, that's a good question. Yeah, I do agree. I'm not a big fan of quick time events in these type of games because, at least for me, if I played like a game like this, it's usually for the story, right? You know, if I want a quote unquote hard game, I'll go play like an Elden Ring or something. But then on the flip side, if I want to do quick time events, I'll play a rhythm game instead.
Al: yeah yes
Al: yeah yeah that's a really good way of putting it yeah um so that the other things are um
Al: it the I mean the difficulty settings I don't really care like I felt like the default difficulty
Al: felt like a good difficulty I think people can people will complain about that no matter what
Al: And there were people clearly just lying about
Al: what their settings were
Al: and showing stuff that only happens
Al: on the easiest settings, right?
Al: The motorbike chase is the classic one
Al: that someone was showing.
Al: Oh, you can't die.
Al: You can.
Al: You absolutely can.
Al: On the default setting, you can die, right?
Al: Like it's just people just out there lying.
Al: I don't care.
Al: And if you care about it being super, super difficult,
Al: you can do that.
Al: That's a thing.
Al: The other thing though was the smell trails.
Al: One of Wolverine's powers is that he's got
Al: a very good sense of smell and can sniff out people.
Al: And what they decided to do in the game with that
Al: is physically show you like a trail
Al: to what you're trying to find.
Al: And some people have been complaining about that
Al: because they're like, oh, it's babying me.
Al: It's holding my hand too much.
Al: I don't really care about that, right?
Al: Because this is not an exploration game.
Al: I'm not in this game to find things
Al: and again, this is probably similar to my feeling
Al: on quick time events.
Al: When I'm in a game and I'm playing Wolverine,
Al: I'm there to stab people.
Al: I'm there to create mayhem.
Al: And walking around linear levels,
Al: following someone,
Al: yeah, I don't care about exploring
Al: and trying to find them.
Al: I'm absolutely fine with it
Al: just telling me where people are.
Vincent: Yeah, I agree. Like, you know, you don't want to be like, you know, you don't want players to give up because they get stuck, like, you know, or some players might get stuck, like, for, I don't know, trying to look for the next thing, but...
Al: yeah and he I yeah and I just like is it over the top yeah probably is over the top I don't I don't
Al: I don't care and I do think that is actually something you can turn off in the settings so
Al: if you do care okay you you can you can care you can turn it off great I i I don't get the moaning
Al: about things that are settings right I get the moaning about the quick if you really want quick
Al: time events to be failable?
Al: Moan about all you want.
Al: I don't get the moaning about, oh, it gives me this thing that I can turn off.
Al: Okay, turn it off then.
Al: Like, if you really care about that, there's a huge list of settings in this game, which
Al: I went through.
Al: Are people not going through settings to see what there are right at the beginning of games?
Al: That's what I do every time I play a game, is I look through the settings and see what
Vincent: Yeah, that's what confused me as well when I learned that, oh, those are all just settings. I mostly play on PC, so that is what I have to do. I have to do that. I go into settings, I adjust the graphics and everything, and I look through all the accessibility stuff too.
Al: yeah but this game also this game also when you click start a game it shows you the settings
Al: so it's not even like it's hidden it's right there you can click on gameplay and see what
Al: the settings are and change your difficulty and for all these things
Vincent: Okay, that was my other thing.
Vincent: It's like, oh, is it one of those games
Al: nope nope nope nope nope before the first cut scene it shows you the settings
Vincent: that just throws you into the action
Vincent: and you don't have a chance to change the settings?
Vincent: Oh.
Al: so I just
Al: I get the
Al: the quick time events
Al: I think it's stupid
Al: but I get why people
Al: would
Al: complain about that
Al: but everything else
Al: just
Al: look at the
Al: like
Al: you're
Al: if you're a gamer
Al: you're looking at the settings
Al: right
Al: we're not just random
Al: you know
Al: it's not like
Al: random people off the street
Al: like you know what you're doing
Al: if you know how to play a game
Al: you probably know how to look at settings
Al: I'm sure you can cope with that
Vincent: Yeah, you want to adjust the experience to suit what you prefer.
Al: exactly
Al: and it's not like
Al: all of the easy access
Al: settings are all on like some of them are not so it's like it's it's a balance of things they've
Al: decided to turn on at the start and I don't think that the default setting should be the hardest
Al: option and so they've tried to create a balance of these are the things that we think should be on
Al: and these are the things that we should think should be off to give the best balance of gameplay
Al: and you can change that if you want sounds like a good experience to me anyway whatever people will
Vincent: well
Al: complain about it no matter what. I think the biggest
Al: I think the biggest
Al: mistake
Al: that they made
Al: was saying that this was
Al: an Insomniac game
Al: because people have expectations of
Al: Insomniac and actually
Vincent: - Yes.
Al: I think that
Al: this goes back, I think this is why
Al: Nintendo don't really focus
Al: on the developers, they just tell you it's a Nintendo
Al: game because if you're told it's a
Al: game by this developer you have certain
Al: expectations going in whereas if you're
Al: just told this is a game and here's the game
Al: then you have the expectations
Al: of that game, right? Like you can't have
Al: Nintendo expectations because they make
Al: so many games and similarly you can't have
Al: Sony expectations because they have so many
Al: different games but you can have an Insomniac
Al: expectation because they just released Spider-Man
Al: 2 and it's such
Vincent: yeah I mean it definitely does happen with nintendo right you you hear like you know
Vincent: once like rumors pop out that like oh this game is being developed by so and so or this npd
Vincent: this group and yeah they people start forming that you know expectations but
Vincent: well hopefully this will at this you know worst cases hopefully this expands what people
Vincent: expect of insomniac games hopefully well as i
Al: yeah maybe I mean that's not necessarily a good thing because because obviously it's not been the
Al: most great experience for a lot of people and so they'll maybe be less positive about insomniac
Al: games going forwards but um the I think the other thing mistake they made was announcing this game
Vincent: Oh, that's fair.
Al: and then not telling us anything about it for five years because all yeah yeah they went here
Vincent: That is, yeah, it just builds,
Vincent: the hype gets built up.
Al: we're releasing a wolverine game and we're like what does that mean and I i've said this multiple
Al: times when I
Al: was like I'm a
Al: little bit worried
Al: about this because
Al: the traversal can't
Al: be as good as
Al: Spider-Man because
Al: it's Wolverine
Al: that's not how he
Al: works and I was
Al: I was right it's
Al: I mean it's it's
Al: fine I don't
Al: dislike the
Al: traversal but I
Al: don't think it
Al: would have worked
Al: in a big open
Al: world which is why
Al: I think that
Al: actually that
Al: level-based design
Al: worked really well
Al: because the it
Al: feels less
Al: restrictive right
Al: if you're in a if
Al: you were in the
Al: the New York that
Al: you were in in
Al: Spider-Man as
Al: Wolverine it would
Al: dreadful you
Al: you would not be
Al: having fun because
Al: you're so you're
Al: just you're just a
Al: person running
Al: around and jumping
Al: it's it's
Vincent: Yeah, you're going to have to like, I don't know, like Grand Theft Auto it or something.
Vincent: So that is just going to become, you know, GTA but melee.
Vincent: But, you know, we're a guy with claws.
Al: Yeah, and that's not what I'm looking for.
Al: That's nothing like Spider-Man.
Al: Anyway, that's enough about Wolverine.
Vincent: Yeah, well, one last thing about Wolverine that I'm curious about.
Al: I enjoyed it.
Al: It's not, it's, yes.
Vincent: Did they allude to or did they just, did they allude to whether this is in the same universe as the Marvel Spider-Man?
Al: there's there's no indication in there's no indication in the game not nothing that I saw
Al: I think outside of the game they have said that it is in the same universe but they said that
Al: spider-man wouldn't be turning up in this game and he did he did not but that doesn't mean that
Al: he that there won't be crossovers in the future I do think there is obviously a problem if you try
Al: and do that because this game is so bloody um you can't cross them over in a game and not have it be
Al: the same...
Al: Like, if Spider-Man 3...
Al: If Spider-Man 3 comes out and Wolverine turns up in it, that immediately changes the age rating of that game, right? Or it just dumbs down the character.
Vincent: Oh, that's fair. Well, you know, they successfully got the Punisher in a Spider-Man movie.
Al: Yeah, and they did that by putting the Hulk in his way so there's no blood.
Vincent: Oh, that's true. That's true.
Al: So, yeah, I don't... I would be surprised if they did that, but it clearly sounds like they want to set up a whole X-Men line of games, right?
Al: You know, with Apocalypse and stuff like that.
Al: I don't know what that means going forwards, but they want something.
Vincent: - Okay, yeah, that's what I was wondering
Vincent: 'cause it does sound like there's gonna be a sequel.
Al: Oh, yeah, I guess it depends on how much they've actually sold and whether they continue on that sequel.
Al: But they've obviously been creating a sequel.
Al: Like, they would have started that already.
Vincent: Yeah, they would have been way deep in development already.
Vincent: Or not deep, but they would have started already.
Al: But it's fine. We'll get the Venom game next and that'll be fun.
Al: Assuming they haven't cancelled it.
Al: All right. That's what we've been up to.
Al: Next up, we have...
Al: I know what you released last month.
Al: We had a very small number of releases in September.
Al: We had Tiny Eden, we had Dragon Shelter, and we had Farming Camp.
Al: One interesting thing about Dragon Shelter, this is the game where I played the demo and I'm pretty convinced that there was AI-generated art in it.
Al: They have been doubling down online saying they don't have AI-generated art.
Al: So, I don't know whether to believe them or not, because that, like, there was...
Al: Most of it was like, okay, I could believe that this is just, like, pretty boring kind of...
Al: But there was one piece in particular that, if it wasn't AI-generated, the artist was an idiot.
Al: And so, I don't know...
Vincent: Oh, but isn't it--
Al: I don't believe them.
Al: But I can't prove otherwise.
Vincent: don't you have to disclose on Steam now
Vincent: if there's AI-generated things?
Al: Yes, exactly.
Al: That's the thing.
Al: But if you can't prove that they're wrong, then you...
Al: If they just say they're not, then what can you do?
Al: And I suspect they have changed that piece of art since the...
Al: In the real game.
Al: I think it was only in the demo.
Al: But I just...
Al: I don't believe them that it wasn't AI-generated.
Al: It was so clearly not...
Al: Like, if a human made that, they made some really stupid decisions.
Al: Like, physically impossible decisions that are clearly obvious if you actually look at the piece of art.
Al: I don't know why anybody would make those decisions.
Vincent: So they denied that it was a generator.
Vincent: They didn't do the whole, oh, it's just a placeholder.
Al: Yeah.
Al: No, they didn't even go...
Al: Which, if they'd said it was a placeholder, that would be one thing.
Al: Disclose that, but I reckon that's what it is.
Al: I do think it was a placeholder.
Al: They are not admitting it, but that's what I think.
Al: I believe that was a placeholder, AI-generated art.
Al: And they have...
Al: I haven't bought the game, so I cannot confirm that they've changed it.
Al: But I would be very surprised if it was the same piece of art now.
Al: And they've done this whole, like, series of...
Al: This is how we designed all these things.
Al: Which very much feels like, oh, people are accusing us of AI-generated art.
Al: We have to prove that we've not done it.
Al: And it's like, I'm not saying your final game has AI-generated art.
Al: I'm saying that piece of art in that demo, I'm convinced, was AI-generated.
Al: That's what I'm saying.
Al: And none of the stuff that they're talking about, of this is how we designed all this art,
Al: none of that had that piece of art that I think was AI-generated.
Vincent: It's always funny to me why you would--
Vincent: if it's meant to be a placeholder, why even use AI?
Vincent: Why not just use like a MS Paint drawing?
Al: well yes I actually think I think that's the thing if you if you don't use ai generated art
Al: for placeholders and you use terrible looking placeholders it's much more obvious when you
Al: still have a placeholder and so you don't miss it the problem is that when you have
Al: ai generated art as placeholders it's much easier to miss because it looks closer to the real thing
Vincent: Yeah, and if it comes out in a, you know, if it accidentally slips by in a early access game, then I think people will be a lot more forgiving. Like, oh, yeah, it's a, you know, it's a beta or it's an early access.
Al: mm-hmm yep
Al: yes yes the the problem is
Al: people have isn't that there was placeholders the problem is that their placeholders were ai
Al: generated that's the problem that people had anyway I haven't played any of these games i
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: do want to play farming camp at some point um I like the look of that game who knows when i'll get to it
Vincent: Oh, Farming Camp does look interesting.
Vincent: Yeah, but I also have not played any.
Al: all right let's talk about some news first up a game you have played Vincent, PokéWilds
Vincent: Yes, I have, although I have not played this update
Vincent: or since the update yet.
Al: that's that's fair I i think most people should probably unless you're like kevin you should
Al: probably wait until the three dlcs are out before playing them I don't think there's enough content
Al: in in any individual one to to satisfy people but this here however if you really love the game
Al: we've got a a new event in pocopia gather pumpkin candy for pump kaboo in Pokémon PokéWilds this time
Al: of year, you might be asked an all-important question,
Al: trick or treat. But in
Al: PokéWilds, you can have the best of both
Al: worlds. The game's next event,
Al: Pumpkaboo's Sweet Surprises, will take
Al: place from October the 17th to
Al: November the 1st, local time.
Al: Pumpkaboo is coming to town,
Al: ready to help you create a
Al: spectacularly spooky vibe.
Al: During the event period, Pumpkaboo will be waiting
Al: for you near rebuilt Pokemon centres,
Al: and you can befriend them to start
Al: collecting pumpkin candy. That's a hard
Al: thing to say, pumpkin candy.
Al: Make sure you've learned the move camouflage from
Al: Zorua at Bleak Beach, because to collect
Al: spoiler alert for PokéWilds,
Al: because to collect any tasty treats,
Al: you'll need to camouflage yourself as objects
Al: and surprise unsuspecting Pokemon.
Al: They'll give you pumpkin candy
Al: as a reward for pulling off
Al: such mischievous tricks.
Al: This is fun.
Vincent: Oh, so you're disguised as an object and you try to sneak up on Pokemon?
Al: Yep.
Al: And then if you surprise them, they will give you candy.
Al: And then you get the candy as all the other events you give the candy to Bumkibu to buy the items.
Al: Of which some of them are fine.
Al: And one of them is particularly good, which is the ghost hologram.
Vincent: Oh, okay, oh, yeah, oh, same pictures of it now.
Al: the other ones are fine there's like a jack-o'-lantern there's some uh halloween inspired
Al: balloons there's a cough agrigus i'm guessing it's a coffin I don't know is there a coffin in
Vincent: Okay.
Al: this game now um uh there's a trevenant statue of some kind and a dusk noir dusclops uh duscal
Al: statue um and uh most importantly that uh ghost hologram the ghost from gen one
Vincent: Oh, I might actually do this event now.
Vincent: This is for a ghost hologram.
Vincent: It looks like a very--
Vincent: or it looks like a piece of decoration
Vincent: that you can actually use for other stuff.
Al: yeah yeah I think this I can't maybe my second favorite event thing second to the sudowoodoo
Al: thing for uh april fools the wacky waving sudowoodoo that one was good as well but yeah
Vincent: Oh, yes, that was a good one.
Al: this is this is fun fun little thing speaking of halloween events hallow kitty island adventure
Al: have their spooky celebration or month month of mischief kuromi takes
Al: over spooky season with trick-or-treating new potions kurumi fied friends and a cafe makeover
Al: so we've also got a fun little halloween event for hello kitty island adventure
Vincent: Oh, interesting.
Vincent: I have to admit, this is one game where I do have it.
Vincent: I picked it up on sale, but I have not started this yet.
Al: can't believe you own a game and you've not played it shocking you'd never find me having hundreds of
Al: them uh next the ever expanding never ending backlog next up we have a release date for
Vincent: It's on the old backlog.
Vincent: Yes.
Al: keep watering that is coming out on the 8th of october which is the day after this episode comes
Al: over the top and stressful
Vincent: well this one does look pretty interesting looks very you know like a not um yeah not yeah
Al: they say it's cozy I really want to know how they think this game is going to be cozy
Al: but i'm gonna have to play it before I make a
Vincent: The only way this could be cozy is if it's slow-paced enough.
Vincent: But looking at the screenshots where there's timers,
Vincent: I don't see how it's going to be cozy.
Al: yeah I i wonder if it's one of these things where it's just like nothing really dies so there's no
Al: like the only disadvantage to doing things slowly is that you just don't get as much as you would
Al: have but you you know you're just continuing on and if you do things you do things I suspect that's
Al: what it will be but some people will just find that automatically stressful it's like i'm not
Al: doing this the most
Al: efficient way possible
Al: therefore it's
Al: stressful
Al: yeah
Vincent: Yeah, it's going to be like, oh, no, now I have to wait until a whole other year to get this crop.
Al: well yeah I don't even
Al: know if it's going to be
Al: the case of like that i
Al: don't know whether it
Al: will be that big I think
Al: it might just be like i
Al: don't I don't know
Al: there's lots of
Al: different it's it looks
Al: to me like it's you
Al: build up something in a
Al: short period of time as
Al: a like a single run like
Al: it feels like a roguelike
Al: to me um but they call
Al: it an incremental idler
Al: they're not calling it
Al: it feels like that to
Al: me where it's like you
Al: spend 10 minutes doing
Al: this thing and then you
Al: do it again in a
Vincent: Oh, yeah.
Vincent: Yeah, faster farm.
Vincent: Yeah, more-- oh, you push your farm further.
Vincent: OK, I see now.
Al: we shall see there's also a massive skill tree
Al: I think it starts up small so I don't it looks like you're not going to see the whole skill tree
Vincent: And just look-- that skill tree does
Vincent: look pretty intimidating.
Al: and you aren't the it adds because I think part of the problem of skill trees and how they feel
Al: intimidating is when you have the whole skill tree visible from the start whereas when I was
Al: looking at the videos of this I saw things appearing when you unlocked something so it
Al: don't see the other things until you've unlocked the previous ones before them
Al: which I think will make it a bit better
Vincent: OK, that's fair.
Vincent: You're not starting to min max and plan out your build right away.
Al: yeah exactly next up luma island is coming to playstation and xbox don't know when they
Al: haven't said when but it's coming there you go that's the news that's it
Vincent: That's the other PlayStation box.
Vincent: No Switch yet, or Switch 2, or no Nintendo console yet.
Al: I can't remember whether it was or no it's not on switch and they've not announced anything about
Al: that so who knows it might just be that they are doing it they've just not announced it but I find
Al: it weird when they're like this is this this this game has been out for a while now and they're only
Al: now announcing that it's coming out but they're not doing it late enough to tell you when it's
Al: coming out but they're not doing it early enough that it's half if you wanted it on these but you
Al: thought it might not come out in them you just buy it on steam like it feels like the worst time to an
Al: ounce it is just randomly without giving you when it's coming out
Vincent: yeah well at least I think this one at least you know I think I agree some of those other games that
Vincent: do this is kind of strange but at least this one they have a good reason is because they have
Vincent: cross-play across platforms so maybe they're like oh yeah if you really like this game and
Vincent: you have a friend that doesn't have a pc but has a xbox or it has a playstation now you can
Vincent: start warming them up to it but still you would probably just announce it
Al: well speaking of release dates grave seasons have made a grave error they're delaying their game but
Al: they have announced a new release date don't do that don't do that so it's now coming out in march
Al: march 9th 2027 and they say the truth of the matter is porting a game to consoles is tough
Al: especially when it's your first major title we've learned a lot about the process and we tackled
Al: some very important changes to our game that helped optimize it for controllers and consoles
Al: such as a radio menu to give you ease of access and a button that you
Al: can hold down to rotate on farming plots extra time has meant we've optimized the game so it
Al: will run well on the switch yay and also on an even wider range of computer specs um yeah don't
Al: don't announce a release date when you're having like this is it's a constant thing and I say this
Al: all the time especially if you're porting a game to consoles do not announce a release date unless
Al: it's ready unless you know you can release on that date unless you could release tomorrow do not tell
Al: as when it's coming out
Al: because they're just going to have to delay it again.
Al: Like, it just, you know that there are problems.
Al: You know it's a difficult thing to do.
Al: You know you've not managed it this time.
Al: What makes you think you're going to manage it
Al: for your next arbitrary deadline?
Al: It's not going to happen.
Al: And even if it does,
Al: you'll be the rare one that manages it, right?
Al: Like, this is, don't announce release dates.
Al: Don't do it.
Vincent: Yeah, also, it seems so it's releasing multiple platforms, right?
Vincent: And they said that they're extra time for meant for running well to switch.
Vincent: I think that makes sense.
Vincent: It's a different platform and even a wider range of computer specs.
Vincent: But if you look at the system requirements, they just says it just requires a 64-bit processor.
Al: yeah yeah yeah I just I feel like you'd I get that I get that people are new to certain parts
Vincent: I was just kind of strange that they don't even, like, list out the requirements.
Al: of game development right like not everybody knows all these things but it cannot be a surprise
Al: the game development is hard it cannot be a surprise that things take longer than people
Al: expect. Games are
Al: Games are always delayed. People
Al: seem to think that they are going to be the unique
Al: one that's special and they don't
Al: have delays.
Al: It's going to take longer than you expect.
Al: It's development.
Al: Software development in general takes
Al: longer than you expect. And game
Al: development in particular is
Al: harder than other software development
Al: because there's so many different things
Al: that can go wrong. I do web
Al: development and even that's hard and that's just
Al: buttons. Button does
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: things. I don't have to deal with physics
Vincent: .
Al: and it's already hard enough.
Al: Just stop being optimistic.
Al: You're not going to be the ones that manage to do this
Al: better than other people.
Al: Just make the game.
Al: And I get it's hard because it's hard to build up hype for games
Al: when you don't have a release date.
Al: But the problem is that if you constantly delay,
Al: that makes people frustrated as well.
Vincent: Yeah, and I guess at least they didn't do the thing where they just release on one platform and delay the other, but I don't even know if that's going to be better or worse.
Al: yeah i'm i'm always mixed on that I get why people complain about that but also like maybe
Al: it's better you have the game out somewhere I don't know they're also it doesn't sound like
Al: they're actually ready to release on steam either because they said we're content uh finished but
Al: we're polishing and fixing up bugs there's going to be a big bug that takes them ages to fix right
Al: like these things are not the best way is they called this this post grave seasons launch date
Vincent: Oh, yeah, just scrolling through the...
Al: final final V2 for real
Al: that's just asking for a
Al: another delay right like
Al: come on you're tempting
Al: fate stop it what is it
Al: with developers and
Al: stressing me out about
Al: these things all right
Al: next up speaking of
Al: release dates like your
Al: frontier have announced
Al: their 1.0 is coming out in
Al: the 4th of November I
Al: actually believe them
Al: because that's only a
Al: month away I think if
Al: you're announcing if you're
Al: announcing a release date
Al: about a month away I
Al: think your game's probably
Al: ready to go you're
Al: probably just because I
Al: think that is the ideal way
Al: to do it is you get the
Al: game ready and then you
Al: give yourself about a
Al: month of hype release hype
Al: and then it means if
Al: there's any final last
Al: minute things that you
Al: notice then you can do
Al: that but don't go like
Al: yeah don't assume it's
Al: going to be fine give
Al: yourself about a month
Al: but be ready right your
Al: game needs to be ready
Al: when you announce the
Al: release date
Al: well that's the thing
Vincent: It's worked for Nintendo.
Vincent: Recently, they've been just announcing their games.
Al: think about the amount
Al: of negative press they
Al: got on games they
Al: announced and then
Al: dates
Al: well maybe I mean
Vincent: Yeah.
Vincent: They learned their lesson.
Al: Pokemon
Vincent: Well, actually, they've learned for the most part,
Al: what are they doing
Al: yeah yeah
Vincent: not every aspect.
Al: no I think you're right
Al: in general they are very
Al: good at that now they
Al: will just announce a game
Al: when it's ready and
Al: they'll tell you when it's
Al: coming out and then it'll
Al: come out on that game
Al: let's ignore Animal
Al: Crossing's New Horizons
Al: I don't know why I gave it
Al: a plural there it's not
Al: Animal Crossing's
Al: Animal Crossing. She
Al: should be Animals Crossing.
Vincent: Yeah, animals, animals.
Al: Which is that?
Al: So, do you know about the...
Al: I don't know whether you know, I'm just, like,
Al: it feels like you like different languages.
Al: Any idea why it's Animal Crossing?
Al: Like, do we know what the translation...
Al: Is that the literal translation?
Al: Let's have a look.
Vincent: Um, I'm not sure actually. I don't know. I've never never come across that theory yet
Al: Like, what is the Animal Crossing meant to be?
Vincent: I guess is it the well, what was the?
Vincent: The first game was the n64 one, right? I
Al: So it looks like the literal translation of the Japanese name is Animal Forest.
Al: That makes sense.
Al: Why? Crossing.
Al: So the English title signifies the interaction or crossing paths between a human player
Al: and a community of anthropomorphic animal villagers.
Al: No, I don't like, I don't, yeah, no, that's very unsatisfying.
Vincent: Yeah, when I think of crossing, I think of like a very busy intersection, not the literal crossing of humans and animals.
Al: Yeah.
Al: Someone online says crossing is often used in the names of villages, towns, forests in the US.
Vincent: never come across a town that's
Vincent: like crossing
Vincent: I have seen like you know strip malls
Vincent: or plazas that named crossing
Vincent: but not like
Vincent: a town or a village
Al: Well, Vincent, you are now American, so you have to speak for all Americans. That's how it works, right?
Vincent: oh that's true
Vincent: it's going to be definitive
Vincent: there's like one
Vincent: nearby it's called like
Vincent: crossing in its name
Vincent: and it's like a shopping
Vincent: center with like a movie theater
Vincent: and a bunch of stores and what not
Al: and I guess that is kind of like a center of community there kind of like the idea behind
Al: animal crossing all right I don't I don't like it but at least there's something there
Vincent: Well, I guess I could see that.
Al: animal forest would have been good why not just that
Vincent: Yeah.
Vincent: Yeah, it still conveys the same meaning,
Al: who let the americans decide on the name there come on that's bad
Vincent: but I don't know why they changed it.
Vincent: Maybe-- yeah.
Al: yeah probably uh yes that's like your frontier coming on the fourth of them
Vincent: Yeah, I'm going to assume it's the Nintendo of America
Vincent: that did the translations there.
Al: november Meadgard having its their early access is coming out in november just november okay cool
Al: I i yeah well that's the thing I don't know why you would do this why you would do this whole big
Vincent: It's a month away.
Al: thing of like oh it's coming out in november but not give us a date like that sounds to me like
Al: you're not ready like november
Vincent: it's yeah they're very eerie where they're like oh all right we'll we'll see um how um
Vincent: how uh hype I don't know I guess they want to say oh is zelda gonna take up a lot of space
Vincent: we want to release in between yeah we might be busy yeah we have I think everything it's gonna be
Al: yeah I think if you have to worry about that don't release in november
Al: right like that's you know also we have dates for both of those games now so
Al: so I don't yeah what are you waiting for uh they originally weren't going to be releasing
Vincent: everything big
Vincent: in November
Vincent: should have a
Al: in early access so what they say is we want to bring mead guards to its full potential and
Al: for all our players early access gives us the opportunity to build upon what we've created
Al: so far continue listening to your feedback and shape mead guard to do something we can
Al: all be proud of hey you can do that without early access as well just just saying like
Vincent: Yeah, oh wait, so was it originally they were supposed to release, they were supposed to not do early access and now they're saying, oh, it's going to come sooner than expected, but it's early access.
Al: yeah
Al: they haven't explicitly said it's earlier because they don't think they had a release date previously
Al: but that is certainly the implication I suspect it's more
Al: I think what happens sometimes with games is as we've talked about development is slower than you
Al: expect and so they get to the point where they're like oh we kind of wanted to release this year but
Al: we're not ready oh you know what let's do early access
Al: yeah yeah it's the break
Vincent: No, there's always the early access button.
Al: break glass in case of early access I yeah it just okay we've talked about it we've talked about
Al: early access we've we've heard opinions we've had opinions all right next pathless woods it's been
Al: 21 months since our last update on the default branch during that first of all that's way too
Al: inside baseball just say our last update right like nobody no most people don't care about your beta
Al: branches right go away during that time we tried every avenue we could to find a way to keep working
Al: we're sorry for the long wait and grateful that you're still here uh yeah they're releasing a
Al: major update um which for some reason they decided to call 0.6.1.7 it's very catchy
Vincent: Why not just come up with like if it's such a major update, come up with a nice marketing name for it?
Al: Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
Al: And, you know, 21 months with no updates on an early access game.
Al: People definitely would have thought this was dead by now.
Al: But 21 months is nearly two years.
Vincent: I mean, it kind of shows, you can see here that the all time peak was over 1800 players and the 24 hour peak is just 76.
Al: Two years is a long early access full stop.
Al: all reviews is mostly positive recent reviews mostly negative
Al: this has not gone down well this update I don't think
Vincent: Yeah.
Vincent: Well, what's the recent reviews anyways?
Vincent: Like, how recent are the recent reviews,
Vincent: given there's no updates?
Al: uh recent reviews it's last 13
Vincent: Okay.
Vincent: - Hmm.
Al: a week and a bit ago.
Vincent: There's a lot of reviews about technical issues
Vincent: and complaints and glitches.
Al: yeah yeah there's some people complaining about the flow in the game and some glitches and some
Al: stuff like that but yeah it's uh someone posted a year ago let this game cook for a few more years
Vincent: Oh, well, they've taken advice to heart.
Al: yeah it's it's just interesting how 80 of overall reviews are positive but 38 of the last month's
Al: are positive now granted the last month has only had 13 reviews so maybe that's just a but that that
Al: sounds to me like there's been an issue in the in the latest update with people talking about
Vincent: Yeah, or the ones that are playing are the hardcore ones that are like, okay, I'm going to use it as a way to give my feedback to the developers.
Vincent: Well, hopefully this update fixes a lot of the issues.
Vincent: It sounds like there's also a lot of just like, you know, runs poorly type of reviews.
Al: Yeah. So it looks like, it looks like they stopped development in April of 2025 or slightly before
Al: that. I'm trying to, and that was a year into early access. And then they were silent for a
Al: year. Their studio ran out of funds at the end of 2024. And then April of this year, they announced
Al: that they're back, but this is their first big update since then. So yeah, I don't know. It sounds
Al: like people really like
Al: the game
Al: like what the game
Al: could be
Al: but most people are saying
Al: maybe don't play it
Al: just now
Al: maybe wait till 1.0
Al: which is
Al: is never great
Al: well
Al: game development's hard
Vincent: Yeah, that's the general vibe I'm getting to from just reading.
Al: I once heard someone say
Al: they try
Al: try to be positive
Al: on on games
Al: because what they say is
Al: it's a miracle
Al: that any game
Al: ever gets made
Al: because of how hard
Al: and this was a game developer
Al: talking
Al: because of just how
Al: how complicated games are
Al: and so I tried to be
Al: a bit more positive
Al: on these things
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: next up
Al: oh farm to table
Al: their major update
Al: number one
Al: uh
Al: it adds a bunch of stuff
Al: but there's only one thing
Al: I care about
Al: and that's controller support
Al: woo
Vincent: Woo!
Al: finally
Al: there you go
Al: should have been in
Al: the first version
Al: also they say
Al: a better steam deck experience
Al: yeah
Al: controller support
Al: will make it better
Al: on the steam deck
Al: and there's a lot of other things
Vincent: - Oh yeah.
Al: in the update as well
Al: but they're only really things
Al: if you
Al: you'd care about
Al: if you played the game
Al: that's the news
Al: we've also got three new games
Al: that we're going to talk about
Al: and just
Al: I want to just say this
Al: just now listeners
Al: this
Al: I cut out a lot of news
Al: because there was so much news
Al: so
Al: I'm just warning you
Al: we might also have
Al: a lot of news next week
Al: and if a lot of news
Al: comes out this week
Al: I might need to do
Al: a news only episode
Al: the week after
Al: to catch up
Al: because
Al: for some reason
Al: this is the time
Al: for everybody to talk about games
Al: I don't know why
Al: it's October
Al: it's not June
Al: right? June's the time to talk
Al: about all your games. Not October.
Al: This is meant to be the quiet time.
Vincent: Well, I think now is the time where like a lot of the either get your games out now before the busy holiday season, or if you're not going to make your release this year, announce it now that you're pushing off.
Vincent: There's not much for 2026 left.
Vincent: So all your 2026 release dates are going to get announced.
Al: Yeah, yeah, but most of these were not most of these were not delayed
Vincent: Oh, or I guess they want to get it out before the busy holiday or before November kicks off.
Al: yeah yeah that's true that's true all right our first new game is animo I think it's meant to be
Al: pronounced uh any any because i'm guessing it's meant to be like anime monsters animo
Al: maybe I don't know i'm gonna go with animo animo is a free-to-play next-gen creature-catching
Vincent: amiibo, but with N and M.
Al: open-world rpg please put more words in that description explore the vast continent of idol
Al: twine with unique animo unlock new abilities travel to a sky-floating metropolis meet other
Al: pathfinders and battle in exciting competitions choose your animo and begin your epic journey
Al: this game has 23 000 reviews on steam how have I not heard of this before so this was sent in by
Al: listener jack thank you for letting us know about this game I don't know how this is so big and i
Al: only just heard about it it came out in the middle of september had you heard of it
Vincent: I have not as well.
Vincent: I'm looking through this.
Vincent: There's a lot of reviews and a lot of players for this game,
Vincent: but I have not heard about this as well.
Vincent: It has a very Palworld-y vibe.
Al: I was going to say it feels like a kid-friendly Palworld, right?
Al: Like, it's like, and this is going to sound so stupid,
Al: but it feels like Palworld without the guns,
Al: which is going to sound stupid to people who are like,
Al: but isn't Palworld just Pokemon with guns?
Al: But it's not.
Al: We all know that it's not.
Al: It's more than that.
Al: It's much more crafting and focused.
Al: But this feels much more like the graphics definitely feel Palworld-y,
Al: and it feels like that's what they're trying to do,
Al: without the kind of gun, the violent.
Al: Well, it's still violence.
Al: It's creature collecting, so there's battles,
Al: but it's not the same thing as just giving your creature a gun.
Vincent: Yeah. Yeah, it's just like, okay, what if we make it more, yeah, take out the controversy of the guns? I mean, they have, like, they're still, the design, I mean, I don't want to say the design looks similar, I want to say it's, you know, there's only so many ways to design creatures, but, you know, you got your, what looks like evolutions, you got your types, you know.
Al: it's not even the creature designs right like I i find the creature design thing yeah tired i'm so
Al: bored of people like oh this this pal looks like a pokemon I don't care right no they both look
Al: like whales shut up um it's more like the the world and the the character design it just there's
Al: I mean I guess it's maybe the kind of like 3d anime style they're doing maybe they're both
Al: just similar because they're both designing off the same sort of idea um but that's exactly what
Al: I call it.
Al: Um, there is farming in this game, so there we go, but, uh, it's free to play, so there's
Al: that.
Vincent: Is it an MMO or I guess, or is it like a gacha?
Al: I think it, I think it is an MMO, because it's tagged as multiplayer and open world, so maybe,
Al: maybe?
Al: They didn't say that in the description, though, let me read the longer description.
Al: I'm enjoying the fact that they just throw this fluffy looking sheep and it turns into
Vincent: Yeah. Oh, there are some, going down to the reviews, there are some mentions of, well, some mentions of AI use, but more concerningly, some security risks are being flagged in the reviews. I don't know how legitimate these are, but.
Vincent: Let's see, breaks GDPR by putting data collection on your PC that survives uninstall. They do not disclose anti-cheat, but they use kernel level anti-cheat.
Al: Oh, fun.
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: Ah, so it won't even work on my Steam Deck then.
Al: It does say, no, it says on Steam Deck,
Al: on the Steam page, it does say
Al: uses kernel level anti-cheat.
Vincent: Oh, or maybe this is an old one.
Vincent: Maybe they just updated it.
Vincent: Oh, no, this is October 2nd.
Al: Requires manual removal after game uninstall.
Al: Oh boy.
Al: It says it's playable on the Steam Deck,
Al: but I thought there was no kernel level anti-cheat on there.
Vincent: That's what I thought, too.
Al: Let's see, their compatibility is playable.
Al: Some functionality is not accessible
Al: when using the default controller.
Al: It requires using the touchscreen or a virtual keyboard.
Al: Shows mouse, keyboard, or non-Steam Deck controller icons.
Al: Entering some text requires manually
Al: invoking the on-screen keyboard.
Al: Some in-game text is small.
Al: The game has minor graphics display issues on Steam Deck.
Al: All functionality is accessible
Al: when using the default controller configuration.
Vincent: Yeah, and it has a platinum rating on ProtonDB, so.
Al: This game's default graphics performed well.
Vincent: Well, that was an interesting thing.
Vincent: I was scrolling through the reviews.
Al: Yeah. Okay. Interesting. I don't know how I feel about this game in general.
Vincent: Yeah, and also that I somehow slipped under my radar, which I think I feel like this would be within both of our radars.
Al: Yeah, I'll keep an eye on it for sure. And I guess we'll see how it continues. If nothing else for the discourse. I will say I think it will be difficult to find the time to slot this into my world because, again, RPG difficult.
Vincent: Oh, I'm not even going to pretend to, you know, be like, oh, I'm going to play this soon.
Vincent: This is a keep on my radar until it actually gets big enough that makes me want to play it.
Al: yeah yeah yeah uh have you played Palworld yet
Al: yeah I i don't think it's going to get any bigger so I think what you mean is put it on a list of
Vincent: That is also still on my backlog.
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: games that you'll probably never play um it's definitely got the like throwing of capturing
Vincent: Yes.
Al: balls at the creatures as well it's like there's a lot similar I don't know what they're throwing at
Vincent: Yeah, there's the one GIF on its theme page where someone throws a ball of sheep looking and it just rolls around and just collects other sheep.
Al: yeah yeah all right so that's out now um next up we have another game that we're going to have to
Al: debate the name the pronunciation nivalis nights nivalis nights nivalis I never think about
Vincent: and Nivea
Al: pronunciations until i'm actually recording I do a lot of looking into these games before the
Al: podcast recording and I never think to
Al: try a pronunciation
Al: grow your business
Al: manage restaurants and nightclubs make
Al: friends and enemies buy and decorate
Al: apartments go fishing and maybe even
Al: find love in a cyberpunk city
Al: that stretches from the ocean to the clouds
Al: yeah it's
Al: restaurant cyberpunk
Vincent: Oh, interesting.
Vincent: I do like me some cyberpunk aesthetic,
Vincent: but interesting there's fishing involved as well.
Vincent: Oh, I guess I see now there's like water.
Al: even dystopias have water most of the time except uh oh it's idiocracy they didn't have water
Vincent: Oh, yeah, I guess.
Al: well no I guess they did eventually have water it's just they didn't understand it
Al: because they did event because event yeah what's the main character did eventually get them to
Al: switch from watering crops with water have you have you watched the film
Vincent: Not sure.
Vincent: Yeah, yeah.
Vincent: Well, I just know what they call him.
Vincent: Not sure.
Vincent: I don't remember his real name.
Al: oh yes sorry yes sorry it's been so long since i've watched it I didn't even get your joke
Al: yes good point all right um I don't think i'm particularly interested in this one
Vincent: Oh, yeah.
Al: cyberpunk is fine as an aesthetic but i've never really been that interested
Vincent: Yeah, I think the cyberpunk sounds like the cyberpunk aesthetic is probably the big
Vincent: differentiating factor of this between this and a lot of other games that are
Al: all right our final new game is Seikyu Let's Go why are all the new games words that we have to try
Al: and guess how to pronounce Seikyu so this is um a spin-off of Tales of Seikyu which is uh um oh what's
Vincent: Seq, Seq, Seq, Saqq?
Al: the word uh give me two seconds I need to go up onto the game to remember the word that i'm looking
Al: for they don't have the word that i'm looking for um what is the pokemon like that uh has the
Al: there's like a japanese type of creature
Al: it's a pokemon like that has this word in its name and it's a name that is used in japanese for
Vincent: - The Pokemon game?
Al: a specific type of creature that's like a spirit
Al: yokai that's yokai is what i'm looking for yeah so this is the game where you like transform into
Vincent: - Temtem, Yokai, watch.
Al: different yokai um you shapeshift and that's how you do your different things anyway that that this is
Al: not that game
Al: a spin-off of that game
Al: so this is
Al: Seikyu Let's Go
Al: which is a spin-off of
Al: Tales of Seikyu
Al: so what they say is
Al: Let's Go is set
Al: also Let's Go
Al: come on this is
Al: why is this Pokemon
Al: Let's Go is set in the same world
Al: you love and adore
Al: a one to four player co-op
Al: camper van trip
Al: through the yokai filled
Al: oh the word was in the description
Vincent: Oh.
Al: through the yokai filled wilderness
Al: snap photos of elusive creatures
Al: decorate your
Al: van together and
Al: help the locals you
Al: meet along the way
Al: camp cook and
Al: clamber across
Al: diverse biomes from
Al: misty swamps to
Al: snowy mountains
Al: adventure awaits so
Al: let's go
Al: what I find really
Al: funny about this is
Al: the the graphics are
Al: just like completely
Al: different from tales of
Al: psyche like tales of
Al: psyche is like kind
Al: of kind of breath of
Al: the wildy kind of
Al: almost realistic type
Al: graphics and this is
Al: like cartoon
Al: silliness like i
Al: don't I don't
Al: understand how this
Al: is meant to be a
Al: spin-off it's like
Al: completely it's
Vincent: I know it's a bit of a very jarring to go back if you go back and forth between the two.
Al: yeah
Vincent: It reminds me of, have you played like Peak?
Al: uh I haven't played it but i'm aware of it
Al: yeah
Vincent: Yeah, I guess the character design reminds me of that.
Vincent: It's like, you know, four players traveling and whatnot.
Al: yeah it's yeah I don't it's I when I saw that there was a spin-off of Tales of Seikyu I was not
Vincent: I don't know if it's like, you know, it's not exactly the same, but it gives me the same vibes.
Al: expecting this.
Al: It's very odd.
Vincent: Well, and then this is also another one where it's released at Q4 2026, which, you know, not much of it left.
Al: Yeah.
Al: True, true.
Al: All right.
Al: Yeah, weird.
Al: This is, again, the same thing as the November releases.
Al: Like, why are you saying it's coming out in Q4?
Al: This is Q4.
Vincent: Yeah, we're in Q4 already.
Al: This game's not coming out this year, right?
Al: Like, that's just asking to delay it till next year.
Al: All right.
Al: This is a long episode, and we've not even started talking about the main topic.
Vincent: Oh, you're right.
Al: All right.
Al: We're talking about augmented reality, virtual reality.
Al: Some people say mixed reality.
Al: I hate the term, but maybe that's what we're having to move to instead of augmented reality.
Al: People don't like the word.
Al: I don't know.
Al: Whatever.
Al: Let's talk about the Steam frame first up, because we both got it.
Al: Like, you got it maybe a week and a half ago?
Vincent: Yes, I think I was in the first batch of Steam Frames that were released.
Vincent: So I got lucky with the reservation queue.
Al: Which is funny because I got the email saying I was in the reservation queue before you got yours, but you got the actual ability to purchase before I did.
Vincent: What did I want to say?
Vincent: Yes.
Vincent: Yes, I got the...
Vincent: Yeah, so it's probably a week and a half ago now.
Vincent: So yeah, I've been enjoying it a lot.
Vincent: You know, it's my first venture into owning
Vincent: a VR system.
Vincent: And I would say, you know, so far, so good.
Al: And this is your first headset that you've owned, but you've tried other ones?
Vincent: Yes, I've tried other ones, you know, like I tried Oculus or MetaQuest.
Vincent: I don't remember specifically which one, but I've tried before, you know, at, like,
Vincent: Friends House and whatnot and, you know, at other, like, activations or whatnot where,
Vincent: like, you do VR experiences.
Vincent: I've done those, but not owning a VR headset.
Al: yeah yeah whereas I had the quest two and then I got the quest I upgraded to the quest three a
Al: couple of years ago um so I guess I can compare it a bit to that um in terms of one thing to bear
Al: in mind is I don't have my I do have my ergonomic uh set but it only came yesterday so i've not set
Al: default headset is much nicer to than the quest's default headset and it'll be interesting to see
Al: how the ergonomic one is um because I got the the ergonomic one for the quest as well because
Al: the these headsets are heavy on your head let's just put it that way and I i don't they can move
Al: around with the default straps um but because the steam frame has like this pad on the back that has
Al: I think it has some of the battery in it.
Vincent: Yeah, I think all the battery is actually back there.
Al: Is it all of it? Okay.
Al: I thought it was just some of it.
Vincent: Or maybe some, I'm not sure.
Al: But because of that, it's much less front heavy.
Al: The Quest, both the two and the three, they're entirely on the front.
Al: So it's like pulls down your head.
Al: Interestingly, I found that you start off getting a really sore neck,
Al: but after a while, your muscles just kind of deal with it
Al: and you stop getting the sore neck.
Al: But I think this is a much better kind of distributed weight.
Al: However, I do want, I'll be interested to see how the ergonomic strap is
Al: because I find it slips a little bit still with the default one.
Al: So hopefully the ergonomic,
Al: because the ergonomic one has the strip on the top of,
Vincent: Yes, so I got the VR, I got the headset, and then my ergonomic kit also came like two days afterwards.
Vincent: And I would say when I first tried on just the headset itself, it felt fine for me.
Vincent: I was like, you know, oh, this works great.
Vincent: I don't know why other people were complaining about this.
Vincent: But then once I actually tried the ergonomic headset, I was like, okay, now I understand.
Al: yeah it's much better I say that I haven't actually used it but in my experience of previous
Vincent: Yes, it definitely helps a lot.
Vincent: Yeah, it doesn't slip.
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: headsets the ergonomic um strap has been better um I think it's I don't know how how i'm gonna
Al: like this compared to the quests one because the quests um ergonomic strap has this thing at the
Al: back which you twist to tighten it on your head which I really like um it's like a really nice and
Al: easy, um, thing, um,
Al: and this one, this, just having a quick look
Al: at this, this does not have, um,
Al: in the same way, so I, I don't know how I'm
Al: going to feel about it, but we'll, I'll need to try
Al: it out and see, um, but I
Al: will, I will say, though, the default
Al: strap, much easier for tightening than
Al: the Quest's default strap, but
Al: not as good as the Quest's ergonomic
Al: strap.
Vincent: Yes. And then does the Quest Organic Restrap, is it just for the headset or does it have anything for the controllers as well?
Al: no that's just yeah it's just the headset there's nothing so it'll be interesting to see how they
Al: feel because you've got a lot the extra hand straps for the thing I don't personally find
Al: that i've had any issues with the controllers both on this and and the quest that need the
Al: straps but it might be like you with the the ergonomic strap where you're like okay I see
Al: why this is good then um if I if I try it out so i'll need to try that um
Vincent: Yeah, I was not a believer in the hand strap as well. I got it. I got the ergonomic package just because, you know, people were saying, oh, it's actually, you know, it makes a difference at least from the reviews that I watched. So I was like, okay, you know, it's 60 bucks. I'm already down a grand on this. What's another 60 bucks worth, right?
Al: Yeah.
Vincent: But, you know, I've been converted on both the head strap and the hand straps in the ergonomic pack. I'd say those are major upgrades I was goes for.
Vincent: As far as to say that those should probably be included in the base package.
Al: Oh, yeah, it's 100% is just to reduce the price.
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: Which is probably the reason it doesn't have a charger in it as well.
Vincent: Yes.
Al: But I don't care because, I mean, who is buying a £1,000 Steam frame
Al: and doesn't already have a charger?
Al: Especially the charger is identical to the Steam Deck charger.
Al: So it's like, is anybody buying this and doesn't have a Steam Deck?
Vincent: Yeah, if you're buying it, especially a niche product like this, you probably already have 10 of these lying around the house.
Al: Yeah. Come on.
Al: I get when people are like, oh, yeah, but I'm spending £1,000, I want a charger.
Al: It's like, okay, sure, but you wouldn't be spending £1,000 if you get the charger as well.
Al: That's not how this works.
Al: They're making it cheaper by not including it.
Al: Now, maybe they're not making it the whole amount cheaper.
Al: Maybe it wouldn't be the price of the charger on top of it.
Al: But, you know, there are so many more things to complain about capitalism,
Al: complaining about your device not including a charger when you already have a million of them
Al: really doesn't feel like the thing to complain about personally.
Al: I think complain about the other things that capitalism is ruining.
Vincent: Yeah.
Al: But you can complain about what you want.
Al: I'm not stopping you.
Al: Complain about what you want.
Al: I just think it's a bit silly.
Al: In terms of controllers, they're almost identical to the Quest's ones.
Al: I was just grabbing them both so I can look at them next to each other.
Al: So on the...
Al: They're not...
Al: I say they're almost identical.
Al: They're almost identical in kind of shape.
Al: So the Steam Deck one is slightly bigger.
Al: It also has a D-pad on the left, which the Quest one doesn't.
Al: And it has extra triggers.
Al: So the Quest one just has two triggers.
Al: One on the front and one on the side.
Al: Whereas the Steam one has two on the front, one on the side.
Al: So it's an extra trigger on each hand.
Al: Plus the D-pad.
Al: I think two extra buttons on the right.
Al: So the Quest has just an A and a B.
Al: But on the left, it has X and Y.
Al: Whereas the Quest has all four of those on one side.
Al: So it's...
Al: I think the only things extra this one has are the D-pad and the two extra triggers.
Al: But because of that, the layout is slightly different.
Al: But it makes it...
Al: It feels more natural to me because it's like essentially the Steam Deck.
Al: Layout, but split.
Vincent: Yeah, I think it sounds like really just the MetaQuest
Vincent: controllers is meant purely for VR,
Vincent: whereas this one is meant for, OK, you can use new VR,
Vincent: but you also use it in--
Al: Yeah. Yeah. Maybe, maybe that's why it is.
Vincent: I haven't tried it yet, but I would
Vincent: suspect you can use these as just regular controllers.
Al: You can. Yeah. Yeah. If you, if you open up a game that isn't a VR game, it just opens it up in a window and you, it switches to like game pad mode where you're just, all of your inputs are affecting the game and you have to like aim outside of the box to come out.
Vincent: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Vincent: Oh, no, if you want to pair this with a computer, for example, and just use this.
Al: oh right I don't know why you would do that
Al: yeah I don't know it's going to be interesting to me to see how the continues because I guess the
Vincent: I don't know either, but I'm assuming you can.
Al: biggest drawback I find on the quest is the the vr software itself it's quite limited in what you
Al: can do with different things um and like it doesn't have any as far as I can see
Al: by default it doesn't have any of like the the non-gaming stuff like you can go into desktop
Al: mode and do stuff there but like the sort of stuff is like oh let's just open up netflix on the side
Al: or something like that you can't really do that just now and I wonder if they're going to lean into
Al: that because I think they might want to do that to expand the scope of who would want to buy one of
Al: these, kind of like your Apple Vision types
Al: stuff of mirroring
Al: your computer and or, you know, putting
Al: a video on the side or
Al: browsing photos, that sort of stuff
Al: and that sort of stuff they could do quite easily
Al: because
Al: it's running on
Al: on SteamOS
Al: there's a lot of, they've done the hard
Al: work of the virtual reality
Al: experience that runs Windows
Al: of applications
Al: they can then expand that a bit more
Al: quite easily with a lot of apps that will
Al: already exist on Linux
Al: yeah
Vincent: Yes, and they have the translation layer, too, for, you know, the running Android apps on Linux.
Vincent: So, yeah, I'm hoping I haven't dabbled too much into that yet.
Vincent: I went into desktop mode.
Vincent: I played around with it, but, you know, just because not having a keyboard makes things kind of difficult.
Al: Although that's changed now that you know you can SSH into it.
Vincent: Yes, yes, definitely.
Al: I also suspect you can probably connect a keyboard via Bluetooth.
Vincent: Oh, you definitely can, but it's more, you know...
Vincent: I mean, I can touch type, but it's just like you're going to have your hands on the controllers and hands on the keyboard makes it.
Al: that's true that's true yeah yeah it's all things like that that they don't support that like things
Al: I mean the quest doesn't either right the quest does some of those things like it supports
Al: browser web browser and it supports a few kind of like youtube and stuff like that
Al: um but it doesn't do the things that say the apple vision plus does where you've got
Al: like it the apple vision plus is quite good in that it will can it can tell where your keyboard
Al: is and it will like show that even when you're in vr and
Al: and stuff like that and obviously it's designed around productivity so there's a lot more features
Al: around the multi-window stuff and apps and stuff like that but I i just it'll be interesting to see
Al: because when the steam deck came out it was very limited and there was a bunch of stuff that was
Al: missing but it has steadily improved and it improved very quickly to start with and then it slowed down
Al: a bit but that's because like people kind of stopped needing new things or wanting new things
Al: And so it kind of just trundled along.
Al: And I wonder if this will do the same thing.
Al: Obviously, this is not their first VR headset.
Al: But because it's the first standalone one, I think a lot of this stuff is new.
Al: Because previously, it was like you connected to your computer for the game.
Al: Like you weren't sitting in your, I can't remember what they were called.
Vincent: Oh, was it the index?
Al: Yeah, that's right. The Valve Index. You weren't popping on your index to, you know, play a game on a big screen.
Al: You were popping on to play the VR games and that was it.
Al: So I think all of this kind of SteamOS VR, I think, is all new to this headset.
Al: So there's a lot of room for improvement and hopefully they will move quickly with that, as we have seen them do multiple times.
Vincent: Yes. And if not, I think the community is probably, since at the end of the day, it is just a computer in the form factor of a VR headset, I think the community could pick up a lot of slack as well, if not.
Al: yeah yeah I hope so and things it feels like it's a lot easier to kind of do custom things than the
Al: meta quest was because the meta quest was very much locked down it was like your traditional
Al: console whereas this is very much like the steam deck but on your face right which as we've discussed
Al: before I personally think there's okay let me go back a bit there's a big problem in consoles versus
Al: PC, where console
Al: are generally good
Al: because they're locked down
Al: and I know that sounds silly but
Al: the reason why I think that
Al: generally makes consoles good is because they have
Al: very limited experiences which
Al: means that they put all the focus on how
Al: those experiences feel and everything
Al: you do on it then is quite good
Al: on PC because
Al: you have everything that's possible,
Al: everything is more difficult
Al: but what I've found is that
Al: SteamOS has done a really
Al: good job of managing
Al: to do both where
Al: if you don't want to do complex
Al: things you don't have to and almost everything
Al: that you need to do on it is
Al: a really nice experience
Al: but you can also then go
Al: into I want to do
Al: crazy stuff mode and
Al: then you can do whatever you want and it's
Al: more awkward and more complicated but
Al: you can do it and it doesn't make the simple stuff
Al: more difficult
Vincent: Yes, I agree.
Al: whereas when
Al: I forget what is your
Al: handheld situations
Vincent: Well, right now it's mainly just I have a Steam Deck and then I have a few other, you know, emulation devices that I don't use as much, but no, no, no, it's just a Steam Deck.
Al: right okay you don't have a windows handheld then because I i have the the ally the ROG Ally X
Al: specifically um which is the one with windows on it although I dual boot it with steam os and
Al: steam os is what I play most of the time and and and windows whatever this version of windows is i
Al: can't remember what they call it it is it's it's really bad right because it's still windows and
Al: they haven't created
Al: like they've created this
Al: visual experience over the top of windows whereas steam os is like yes it's a visual experience over
Al: linux but it's not it's it's an entire it's the entire thing you have to like switch into desktop
Al: mode which is your traditional linux desktop whereas windows is like windows is running
Al: including the entire ui in the background and then it has this ui on top of it
Al: and that means
Al: that because they're relying
Al: on that there's a lot of stuff
Al: that ends up being it just
Al: pops up a Windows window
Al: and you're like I'm not on a
Al: computer why are you showing me a window
Al: with like
Al: minimize maximize close
Al: controls this is not what I should be seeing
Al: on a handheld gaming console
Al: whereas SteamOS doesn't
Al: do that sort of stuff it is
Al: very rare unless you're
Al: specifically trying to do complicated stuff
Al: in desktop mode
Al: it is very rare
Al: that you would see anything
Al: like some games
Al: will load up
Al: in a windowed mode
Al: but there's very few
Al: of them I've found like that
Al: and I think this is
Al: the same sort of thing
Al: with SteamOS VR
Al: where it feels like
Al: they've put the same
Al: amount of thought
Al: into how the experience works
Al: I haven't encountered
Al: a oh that's a weird
Al: looking window
Vincent: Oh, yeah. Yeah, it is very shocking that, yeah, definitely, Valve has locked in that UX, UI, like separation of, you know, okay, if you really want to just game, you don't want to worry about any of the Linux stuff and whatnot, you can go an entire, you can use a Steam Deck or a Steam Frame or SteamOS in general without even realizing that there's a whole, you know, Linux operating system behind it.
Vincent: You can just install the games and that's it, which...
Al: And the key point and the key point is that's the default that should be the default it has to be the default if you want it to be good, whereas Windows doesn't have that.
Vincent: Yes, yeah, it is shocking how Microsoft hasn't locked that down yet.
Al: I think it's because there's they don't want to the way that valve did it was there are just some
Al: features you're just not going to have in that experience until we get them implemented whereas
Al: what microsoft have clearly done is if we don't specifically make it a feature it's going to be a
Al: windows feature and it's just going to show you the windows thing and maybe we'll replace it at
Al: some point they did the same thing with when they switched from um xp to vista when they started chain
Al: how the ui looked you would sometimes have like control panel would just look like it was windows
Al: xp and it would look completely out of place and obviously when they're doing that you can't just go
Al: oh you're not going to have that feature and they didn't want to rewrite everything before they
Al: released the version and that was the decision they made but it meant it felt not good whereas because
Al: handheld gaming consoles are a relatively new thing you don't have to have all those features
Al: to start with you can implement them as you go and especially because you have desktop mode
Al: if there's something that isn't in there you can just go into desktop mode and do it if you really
Al: care about it but the key things are there the features are there when you need them and I think
Al: the problem is that microsoft just aren't willing to do that they aren't willing to go this feature
Al: doesn't exist unless you know where to get it and so that's why they have that so many situations
Al: where it's like we've not created this version in this ui therefore you just get the windows ui
Al: but it just feels bad
Vincent: Yeah, I've never, I haven't had the opportunity to use a Windows handheld yet. But yeah, just from what I've seen online, it's like where like a random pop up will just come on and or you have to go into Windows to do some certain settings and whatnot. It just does not sound like a good experience.
Al: it would just open up control panel again.
Al: And you're like, why am I?
Al: Like, the worst thing about the Windows handheld experience
Al: is settings, trying to figure out where settings are
Al: because there's like five different places
Al: where you can get settings.
Al: And one of them is just Windows control panel.
Vincent: Oh, my God.
Vincent: Yeah, I think that's just the Windows experience in general.
Al: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Vincent: We're like, okay, so in settings, it's in control panel, where is it?
Al: Whereas if you want the settings on SteamOS,
Al: you go to the settings and they're all there.
Al: You have to figure out where the settings are
Al: unless you're running like Bazzite or something,
Al: but that's your own problem.
Al: If you're being complicated like that,
Al: then you're asking for trouble.
Vincent: Well, at that point, if you're running on an operating system
Vincent: that you installed yourself, you probably
Vincent: know what you're doing already, so yeah.
Al: exactly exactly exactly but I do think they should do that better
Al: and they had Bazzite changed from I can't even remember what they have like an underlying
Al: controller mapping layer and they changed which one they were using and it broke how my controllers
Al: worked on my on my ally because I was using bazite because obviously it's it came with windows so i
Al: I had to install SteamOS in the easiest
Al: way was just installing Bazzite
Al: because SteamOS isn't officially supported
Al: on my controller, on my
Al: console yet
Al: but yeah, they just decided to change how it
Al: worked and it broke my controller mapping
Al: so I had to fix that and that is
Vincent: Oh no!
Al: the worst thing and it's like no
Al: this is like being back on running
Al: Arch on my computer when you just
Al: things just break underneath you and this
Al: is why SteamOS is just so good
Al: because they only do things when it's
Al: actually working, they don't just like randomly
Al: change these things from underneath you
Al: yeah
Vincent: Yeah, and they take their time with us, especially with a stable branch where they don't push out updates.
Al: oh yeah, almost
Al: almost too slow
Al: but no, no, no, definitely
Vincent: Yeah, oh yeah.
Al: definitely, I think they're doing things
Al: very well, so my point
Al: is I hope that they do that
Al: for the frame as well
Al: and that we see a good amount of
Al: feature updates over the next
Al: you know, six months to a year
Al: and I hope that they focus on
Al: some of these more
Al: kind of productivity-based
Al: things because I would really love to be able to like stick on the headset and have my game
Al: and also be what like have some youtube videos on the side or something or like you know what i
Al: really one thing that I love for these headsets is being able to watch videos in like imax mode
Al: um because that's not something you can do normally and just being able to have this
Vincent: Oh, yes.
Al: massive screen watch a film that you weren't able to watch at the cinema or whatever so I really hope
Al: do that sort of thing.
Vincent: I do think they will try to do that, and the reason why I say that is because the main difference I've noticed between this and, you know, SteamOS on, like, if you install it on a PC or on a Steam Deck is that they made it much easier to switch to the desktop mode, or to the desktop, where it's just a shortcut.
Vincent: You don't have to, you know, power off and do, like, kind of like a semi-reboot. It is just there. So that makes me think that they could potentially lean into more, you know, non-gaming side of things.
Al: yeah yeah we'll just have to see um I think most people probably shouldn't buy this yet
Al: not just because it's a thousand quid but because there's a lot they've they've they've not proven
Vincent: Oh, definitely not. It's...
Al: themselves yet um I think they have proven themselves with the steam deck um but I don't
Al: think they've proven themselves with with with vr with uh steam os vr yet but hopefully they will
Al: and uh I am willing to be that game changer
Vincent: Yeah, overall, I would say the experience has been great, you know, especially just running games right on the, or directly on the frame.
Vincent: You know, I've, aside from Beat Saber, I've ran the gamut of, you know, your quote-unquote popular, easy-to-run indie games, like your Hades, Dave the Diver, Stardew Valley, those all seem to work great.
Al: I have not and I i don't know how well i'll be able to do that because I don't have a decent
Vincent: But have you tried streaming from a PC yet?
Al: windows pc um I just have my mac which as far as i'm aware it doesn't support yet I haven't tried
Al: yet but the internet says it doesn't support it as of yet um but I don't know whether that's
Al: because the games just aren't supported on mac or whether it's because the dongle itself doesn't
Al: work, but I haven't tried that yet.
Al: I literally got this arrived four days ago.
Vincent: I have tried streaming from a PC and I will say, from what I've seen, generally people
Vincent: have had success streaming from the PC, but I've ran into some issues. I think it's
Al: so from what from what I can see if you don't use a usb 3.2 port that's when people seem to have
Al: issues so anything 3.1 3.0 that's where people are having issues but if you have 3.2
Vincent: Yes, I think that's where I've run into the issue as well.
Vincent: I don't know if it's like, you know, I think it is the USB issue because whenever I plug
Vincent: it in, if I don't have it connected to the device, it just keeps, I keep getting a pop-up
Vincent: that like it's, you know, restarting itself, which I think is like a firmware issue.
Vincent: But also I'm not, I don't know if this is the thing, but I'm also, I'm not using a Windows
Vincent: machine and that may be it as well.
Vincent: Because I do know that they did say that, you know, it does not officially support or
Vincent: the Steam machine is not officially supported yet.
Al: yeah I think yeah yeah but I think they'll they'll definitely get there with that whether
Vincent: And I think it may be like a, you know, Linux firmware issue.
Al: they get there with mac or not I don't know they'll definitely get there with with uh with
Al: linux even if it even if you have to it has to be steam os though there's no way they won't get to
Al: with that like it's it's a bit silly that it's released without steam machine support but
Al: I don't think it's a big issue but it is of it is a bit silly that that's ended up how it is
Vincent: Yeah, I found some workarounds online, but the list of instructions is a little bit too big. I'm just going to wait for them to update.
Al: even if there are legitimate reasons but
Al: yeah yeah fair enough um all right uh I had beat saber on our list but we kind of talked about that
Al: I don't know if there's anything else you want to talk about
Vincent: No, I think we went through all this.
Vincent: I just want to say I've been skeptical of Beat Saber before, but now I'm a certified Beat Saber fan.
Al: good good I feel like beat saber has uh single-handedly pushed people's perception of
Al: vr forward um because it just the number of people are like oh I don't get vr and then they
Al: see beat saber and like I get vr you know um it's it is the reason I actually I know I remembered
Al: you you already know this vincent i've already said this to you but I remembered this week that
Al: this is actually the third time i've bought beat saber because I originally bought
Al: it for psvr on the ps4 uh I got a psvr headset and I bought beat saber for it didn't buy any packs
Al: but I bought it and I i loved it but I hated the cables I just like it was just not fun having to
Al: be in like a specific orientation in a specific place I did not enjoy that and so I bought a quest
Al: two and bought it for that and then obviously bought the quest three and continued using it and now i
Al: as well so I have bought beat saber three times not not many games
Vincent: I will say they did a good, I would say they did a good job of, I don't know, I'm sure they timed this perfectly, but they did do the, you know, they reduced the price, the base price, like, a few months before the Steam frame came out, and then they ran a discount, like, right when the Steam frame came out, because they probably knew people are going to buy this.
Al: yep and they've there's no it's not a coincidence that they've just announced their uh their update
Al: coming next year as well yeah I don't know if it's that or not because I feel like it's a long
Vincent: They've been sitting on that probably, like, all right, I'm going to wait for a new VR headset to come out.
Al: time in the future because it's spring next year so it's quite you know we're talking six months
Al: until the game until the update comes out so I feel like it's almost like they announced it
Al: earlier than they would have otherwise because of the steam frame coming out now but
Al: i'm excited for the update the the new mode the hand tracking mode um oh that's the other thing
Al: i've not figured out hand tracking on the the steam frame I believe it does have hand tracking
Al: but I can't figure out how to do it I haven't spent a huge amount of time trying but on the quest
Al: it just has hand tracking if you don't if you don't turn on the controllers it defaults to hand
Al: tracking and I can't figure out it doesn't seem to do that on the steam frame so I don't know
Vincent: Oh, I haven't done either, but in the, you know, like I said, I've been having some issues
Vincent: with the streaming, but just because the USB dongle keeps resetting itself, so, you know,
Vincent: the stream is a little finicky, but in the other game, in some of the games that I've
Vincent: tried, there is some, it doesn't track your hand, but it does track your hand based off
Vincent: which buttons you're pressing or which you're on the controller, but not, yeah, not full
Al: yeah yeah yeah yeah that's oh it looks like it just doesn't have hand tracking at all
Vincent: hand tracking.
Vincent: Oh.
Al: just now so um I i can't see them not adding it at some point because I think it's it's really
Al: handy especially for when you have like a keyboard up and on the quest i've quite often had the
Al: keyboard up and i've just i'm just tapping away with my fingers on it it's not amazing it's still
Al: a bit fussy but it's easier than using the controllers to like you know your laser mouse
Al: it's much easier to be like just tapping on it in the air so I i feel like yeah
Vincent: Oh yeah, typing in my Wi-Fi password with that laser mouse was very painful.
Al: yeah so I i feel like it i'd be surprised if they weren't working on hand tracking it's a
Al: great feature um okay two more questions about the headset before we talk about a couple of games
Al: but we're probably not going to talk a lot about them because yeah well i'll explain in a minute
Al: um are you have you bought lenses yet because you wear glasses don't know
Vincent: I have not.
Vincent: So this is another thing I've discovered with the Steam frame.
Vincent: I don't know, this is maybe just with my eyes.
Vincent: But when I first put it on, I was like, oh, everything's blurry.
Vincent: And OK, that makes sense, because I wear glasses.
Vincent: But I did find out that just through adjusting it,
Vincent: once I got the ergonomic frame or ergonomic add-on,
Al: Yep.
Vincent: is that at a certain angle, it actually--
Vincent: everything becomes crystal clear without glasses.
Al: Have you made sure that you've changed where the lenses are as well?
Vincent: Yes, I've tried those as well.
Vincent: So there's a certain angle for the headset that works for me
Vincent: that I can see clearly.
Vincent: The problem is that angle means that my nose
Vincent: isn't touching the nose guard thing.
Al: Yeah.
Vincent: So it's not bad, but there is some light that bleeds through.
Vincent: So I will still look into getting those...
Vincent: The prescription lens says.
Al: I, I have ordered some lenses. I did that yesterday because the, the site I was looking,
Vincent: Oh, okay.
Al: what the site that, um, ships to the UK just put them up, um, yesterday. So it says it will be
Al: three to four weeks. So, but, uh, yeah, it will be, uh, I'm looking forward to, I never got it
Al: for my quest because I just dealt with it. Um, but I I'm like, if I'm, if I'm spending a grand
Al: on this new one
Al: I feel like the other advantages
Al: of having the prescription lenses
Al: is because they go over the lenses
Al: in the headset
Al: you're giving it a bit more protection as well
Al: so that if anything gets broken
Vincent: Oh, that's-- oh, that's true.
Al: it's the replaceable lenses
Al: rather than the non-replaceable lenses
Vincent: OK, I need to-- once again, I need
Vincent: to hear about how easy it is to take it on and off
Vincent: so in case if I want to share this with other people.
Al: Yeah, I believe they're just magnetic, and they just pop on, pop off. But I will confirm to you when I get them. Yeah, for the faceplate and stuff like that, yeah, it's really nicely designed, the magnets. Did you put the spacer on?
Vincent: Oh, that's another thing I love about this.
Vincent: It's all magnets.
Vincent: Yes, yeah, I put the spacer on, and then, because you have to, well, there is a bit of disassembly you need to do to put on the ergonomic head strap, but other than that, yeah, everything's just magnets.
Al: right yeah yeah it's really nice all right a few games to talk about first up isle of food
Al: this was the game that I i got a code for a couple weeks ago for my quest headset
Al: and I have tried it and it makes me incredibly motion sick this game um and I i think it might
Al: be because it's so because it's a vr game where you're not walking around specifically yourself
Al: you are using the controller to move it
Al: but also
Al: the movement
Al: is fine, it's just normal movement
Al: with the left analogue stick
Al: but to move the camera
Al: around with the right analogue
Al: stick, it moves in like
Al: 20 to 30 degree
Al: slots, it's not smooth
Al: movement, so you're like
Al: jumping around when you
Al: want to look to the right
Al: you have to like tap, tap
Al: and then you're like boop, boop
Al: And it's utterly horrendous.
Al: Terrific. I can't, like, it's the point where I can't really talk about this game much, because I put it on for five minutes, and I was like, no, I can't, I can't do that. It was just, because it was not smooth, my brain was fighting me, fighting for its life, any time I turned again.
Vincent: So I had a similar experience.
Vincent: I did try No Man's Sky VR.
Vincent: It's the exact same thing where like,
Vincent: as soon as I, you know, everything was great.
Vincent: Sure, you know, access in the menus and whatnot
Vincent: is a little complicated
Vincent: because you have to point to your hand
Vincent: and press buttons.
Vincent: That's fine.
Vincent: But as soon as I started, you know,
Vincent: needing to turn left and right,
Vincent: I was like, oh my God, this is...
Al: and I think that the moving if if yeah I think the thing is that I could probably get used to
Vincent: I mean, you can turn your head to look,
Vincent: but you want to look...
Al: the movement without actually physically moving but it was those jumps in the camera and that's
Al: not that's not oh it just wasn't processing quick that's how the feature works it's deliberately not
Al: smooth and I don't know why they made that maybe it's because they couldn't make it work well
Al: with the resource resource intensive and smooth I don't know it just it's
Vincent: Oh, I will once, I'm hoping once the either they update the dongle or I just, you know, bite the bullet and do the manual fixing myself, I'll report back once I try because I do have other VR games in my library, you know, like Half-Life Alyx and whatnot that I want to try to see how they, is it, are all VR games like that? Or is it just these specific games?
Al: yeah i'll be interesting to see how that goes um the other one to talk about is your wonderful life
Al: so this is the new story of seasons ar game um and I think this is going to be interesting
Al: now generally social media says this looks terrible but also I think that's just because
Al: like people aren't looking for like most people aren't looking for vr stuff or ar stuff right
Al: like most people don't care about these things and so people are looking at going this isn't for me
Al: therefore nobody wants
Al: this
Al: but what I find interesting
Al: about this is
Al: so it's kind of like
Al: Living Room
Al: which is the game
Al: that I talked about
Al: on the podcast before
Al: where it's
Al: you're in your
Al: world
Al: your normal reality
Al: and you have this game
Al: island
Al: sitting in front of you
Al: and you're doing stuff
Al: there
Al: on it
Al: and
Al: kind of
Al: almost like a kind of
Al: god-like figure
Al: kind of like
Al: SimCity type thing
Al: but it's like
Al: physically
Al: feels like
Al: out in front of you
Al: shopping things
Al: and picking things up
Al: and stuff like that
Vincent: Oh, interesting. This is the one, I don't know, do we confirm it? This is meta only for now, right? Are this what's announced?
Al: yeah, that's all they've
Al: announced is for meta, yeah
Al: they haven't announced anything about whether it
Vincent: Hmm.
Al: another reason why i'm keeping my headset just in case it doesn't come out on steam and I have
Al: because i'm i'm gonna have to cover this for the podcast obviously right like
Al: um so yeah it just it's interesting uh I i like I mean I loved living room living room was great i
Al: had I had a lot of fun playing that and being like oh i'm just gonna do my little farming
Al: on my headset and like got this little world what I find interesting is there do seem to be bits on
Al: this game where you're almost
Al: you're zooming into first person
Al: so like most of the game seems to be like
Al: this SimCity view
Al: and then you also seem to
Al: zoom in and do some like
Al: fishing and stuff like that
Al: and also maybe raise a family
Al: and I'm intrigued to see
Vincent: yeah it does I do like that it's it's not the you know I guess a traditional like oh everything's in
Al: which parts are which kind
Al: of interface
Vincent: in first person uh point of view right where like that because that seems to be where most
Vincent: vr games is I like I like this um the aspect of like okay you're like a omnipotent being
Vincent: point of view and you're managing your town that way uh which I do hope that
Vincent: comes to more or more when farming games come to vr I do hope they some of them go that aspect
Vincent: instead of like the first person point of view because you know yeah moving in moving in a first
Vincent: person point of view I feel like that's just kind of you know even if you're used to it
Vincent: a lot of people aren't that just kind of limits the the reach
Al: So I need to look at this update for Living Room and maybe try it out because, yeah, it seems to be very sheep focused.
Al: They have the sheep there and there seem to be aliens that abduct your sheep, maybe.
Al: And some alien animals.
Al: I'm very intrigued by this update.
Al: Maybe it's time to play this game again.
Al: Again, this one is only meta.
Al: There's nothing on Steam yet, but I think this is going to there's going to be like a time period where people aren't making their games for the Steam frame.
Al: You know, they've been developing it with the quest in mind.
Al: And so that's what they're making it for.
Al: And hopefully in a year or two, we'll be getting them on both or maybe just the Steam.
Al: I just, you know, it's like when the Steam deck first came out.
Al: There were a lot people didn't develop for it.
Al: And so it took a couple of years before every game worked on it.
Al: and even now we're still at this
Al: position where sometimes games
Al: release without controller support and therefore you can't use
Al: it but most games
Al: come with it now like it's just
Al: it's one of these things where it's like it's just changed
Vincent: Oh, yeah. I think it's created like a new, you know, before there was no like least common denominator for like PC. But now there's like, okay, the Steam frame settings, at least for the most part, except like for, you know, your AAA games. But for the most part, there's at least a nice baseline to shoot for in terms of performance as well.
Al: yeah yeah for sure um and the other farming vr game that I haven't tried is garden of the sea
Al: um which is obviously a fishing focused game um but yeah I haven't tried that one it looks much
Al: more first persony moving around so I maybe it'll have the same issues as isle of food i'm not sure
Al: but um it is on steam
Vincent: Yeah, oh, it looks like it's a separate entry for the VR game, but there's a bundle where if you get both for the price of one.
Al: Yes. Yes, I believe so.
Al: Oh, yeah.
Al: Oh, that's fun.
Al: In fact, it's 1p cheaper to buy the bundle
Al: than it is to buy the game on its own on my screen.
Al: It's £5.95 for the game or £5.94 for the two games.
Vincent: Oh, that's-- oh, yeah, oh, yeah, same here.
Vincent: Oh, yeah, same here.
Vincent: Yeah, it's $6.99 versus $6.98 for a remote.
Al: And let's see.
Al: It is not verified on Steam Frames.
Al: the promotion lasts until thursday
Al: all right I think that's probably enough for now maybe we'll do another episode when we've
Vincent: Oh, I may try this out.
Al: had more time on them and maybe played a few more games or or stuff but that's probably enough for
Al: now two hours is long enough uh so thank you vincent for joining me um is there anything you
Al: would like to share with the audience?
Vincent: No, thank you for having me.
Vincent: Nothing really specific to share.
Vincent: I guess just if you want to get a Steam frame,
Vincent: I would say definitely.
Vincent: If you're a tinkering type, then yes.
Vincent: If not, yeah, hold off on it a bit.
Al: I think I would say just don't get it.
Vincent: Like I said, if you were the person
Vincent: who would want to get a Steam frame,
Vincent: you probably already know.
Vincent: You probably don't need other people telling you
Al: exactly exactly this is this is what I i it's the same sort of thing when I talk about having kids i
Al: tell most people don't have kids because the people who should have kids are the ones who say
Al: no I will have kids despite you telling me not to it's the same thing I don't think you should buy a
Vincent: Okay.
Al: steam frame and if you if you get offended by that and say no no I will buy one then that that's fine
Al: you should all right uh well I don't have my notes in front of me that was silly I closed the tab
Al: I did the outro and I forgot how much I need the notes for the outro you can find the podcast on
Al: tumblr and on blue sky at thspod you can send us feedback on our website harvestseason.club where
Al: you can also find links to everything to do with the podcast including a link to our patreon patreon.com
Al: slash thspod where you can support the podcast and in return get access to our slack vincent's on the
Al: Slack. You can also get access to our
Al: bonus episodes of the podcast, which
Al: has been slow just now, but we will get
Al: more out soon. I think that's
Al: everything. Thank you, Vincent, again for
Al: joining me. Thank you, listeners, for
Vincent: All right, thank you for having me.
Al: listening, and until next time, have a
Vincent: Have a good harvest.
Al: good harvest.
Theme Tune: the harvest season is created by al mckinley with support from our patrons including our
Theme Tune: pro farmers kevin stewart and elisa our art is done by micah the brave and our music is done by
Theme Tune: nick burgess feel free to visit our website harvestseason.club for show notes and links
Theme Tune: to things we discussed in this episode
Al: Oh, my voice is dying by the end there.
Vincent: [laughs]
Al: That's what happens when it's late.